* [theme]
>> Dianne: Tonight on a special
edition of Dragons' Den...
The Year of The Dragons.
We followed David...
>> David: Hey, welcome to
Dave Chilton's house.
>> Dianne: Arlene...
>> Man: Very good.
>> Dianne: Jim...
>> Jim: We're going
to have some fun today.
>> Dianne: Bruce...
>> Bruce: The [bleeped]
this guy's, I'm not stressed.
>> Kevin: All right!
>> Dianne: and Kevin
for an entire year.
>> Kevin:
Oh, the O'Leary's good.
>> Dianne: Find out
how they run their empires.
>> Jim: Woo-hoo!
>> Dianne:
and how they let loose.
>> David: Woo!
>> Dianne: We'll reveal
stories you don't know...
>> Kevin: I think I let
celebrity get to me.
>> David: I don't cook,
I've never used the oven.
>> Dianne: and peek into
their private lives.
>> Arlene: Can you say hi
to everybody?
>> Girl: Hi!!
>> Bruce: Change it up,
let's go!
>> Dianne: The Dragons, like
you've never seen them before.
>> Kevin: Oh, it hurts.
[theme song "Put Yer Money
Where Yer Mouth Is" by Oasis]
* Put yer money
* where yer mouth is
* Yer mama said
* that you was real
*
* Ready or not
* come what may
* Yer bets are going down
* for judgement day
* So, put yer money
* in yer mouth
* and your hands
* right upon the wheel
*
* Watch out
* Hey, watch out
*
>> Dianne: Hello and welcome
to this special edition
of Dragons' Den:
The Year of The Dragons.
For the past twelve months,
we were given an intimate,
behind-the-scenes look at life
outside the Den to find out
what it really means
to be a Dragon.
>> Jim: And I see this bunch of
junk and that's what it is,
a bunch of junk and
you've wasted your time.
Our time and your money.
>> Dianne: Inside the Den,
Jim Treliving can shoot to kill.
>> Kevin: What do you
really think, Jim?
>> Jim: I'm really upset.
>> Dianne: He's also one of
the Den's biggest spenders.
>> Jim: Zoey, I'm going
to throw you an offer.
>> Zoey: Okay.
>> Jim: How about
$125,000 for 25 per cent,
but I want a 50 per cent say
with you in the business?
>> Arlene: Wow.
>> Zoey: Yeah!
>> Jim: I'll make you
an offer at 21 per cent
for a million dollars.
>> Tanya: That's perfect.
I say yes.
>> Girl: Thank you very much.
>> Jim: Thank you.
>> Arlene: Well done.
>> Man: Thanks, guys.
>> Dianne: Jim's deal-making
chops afford him this million
dollar view from a two-storey,
penthouse condo in Vancouver.
Each morning,
dressing for success
is first on his to-do list.
>> Jim: I walk in and
I pick my suit right away.
And it's based on a lot of
who I'm going to see and
who I'm going to talk to. So,
if I'm going to be sitting with
a bunch of people in a business
deal, I'll have a dark suit and
and a tie that's really strong.
It's not work.
To me, I don't go to work.
I don't feel like
I'm going to work.
>> Dianne: Work can be a breeze
when it means jetting off to
meet with George Melville, his
business partner of 40 years.
>> Jim: Whoa.
Look at the sign, George.
>> George: Yeah, pretty cool.
>> Jim: Woo!
>> Dianne: Years ago
they listed Boston Pizza
on the Toronto Stock Exchange.
>> Jim: We're going
to have some fun today.
>> George: Okay.
>> Dianne: They're ringing
the opening bell to celebrate.
>> All: 3, 2, 1.
[bell rings]
>> Jim: I love doing business.
I love something new every day.
...Whoo-hoo!
I guess that's my major
feature is that I'd be bored
if I went to the same thing
over and over again
and I don't think of myself
as the age I'm at.
...Good job. Good job.
>> Dianne: On paper,
Jim's a senior citizen, yet he
travels like a rock star between
his three homes and his office,
which is just about anywhere.
>> Jim: My wife and I travel
probably in the neighbourhood
of 190 to 220 days a year.
I know my routine.
I get to the same hotel.
Everybody knows me.
It's very easy the way
I travel because I travel
first class or private.
>> Dianne: He's personally
overseeing Boston Pizza's
massive expansion
into the U.S. and Mexico.
>> Man:
Here comes the good stuff.
>> Dianne: Jim isn't just
a Boston Pizza figurehead,
he meets every franchise owner
to enforce quality control.
>> Jim: The first beeline I make
is to hit for the kitchen.
...How are you doing?!
>> Cook: Good, how are you?
>> Jim: I'm doing good.
The back of house as we call it,
because if our stuff
isn't clean,
then everything else is a mess.
...Crystal clean, crystal clean.
>> Dianne: Ever the Dragon,
he still has an eye
for the small details.
>> Jim: This is time to go
that's for sure, it was a good
idea 15 years ago but now
it's time to move on.
>> Man: It gets no play.
>> Dianne: There is one thing
that stands out about Jim.
[indistinct]
>> Dianne: He's always
got time to meet customers.
>> Woman: Can I get
a picture with you?
>> Jim: You absolutely can.
>> Dianne: Especially for
these Dragons' Den fans
visiting from Canada.
>> Jim: Hi, Honey,
is this your doll? Wow.
That's a cutie.
...We lived in a small town
so everybody knew everybody.
...There we go,
now we're talking!
>> Woman: Thank you.
>> Jim: My mother used to say to
us, you say hello to everyone.
>> Woman: Say cheese!
>> Jim: My dad's favourite
saying was you'll meet
the same people on the way up
as you do on the way down.
>> Woman:
It was great to meet you.
...Nice to meet you, too.
>> Dianne: Jim recently put that
kind of wisdom into his own
book called Decisions.
It outlines how he grew
from a small town Mountie
to a big-time pizza king.
>> Jim: Two words are the most
important thing in the world
to me are 'common sense' and
I try to show that to my kids
and talk to them about it
because you can have all
the education in the world.
You can have all
the ideas in the world.
You can have everything and
all the money in the world.
If you don't have common sense,
it's not going to work.
Who do you want this to?
>> Dianne: As a bestselling
author, Jim finds himself
flexing some new muscles.
>> Jim: This is the launch day
for my book. Finally, finally,
finally I get to launch my book.
Just came out, first day.
Sales are great.
Going mad signing
lots of autographs.
My arm's getting really sore.
>> Woman: Dragons' Den rocks.
It's a very good show.
>> Jim: I love that show.
>> Dianne: Jim has made a point
of sharing his incredible
success and wealth.
>> Man: Smile. Nice. Thank you.
>> Dianne: Last year,
Jim and his wife
Sandi donated $1 million
to a Toronto hospital...
>> Woman: Pamela, welcome back
to Vancouver Island.
>> Dianne: and he helped raise
a whopping 4 million at this
star-studded gala in Victoria.
>> Jim: My best buddy
right here.
He's doing a great job!
...You can get involved
in organisations;
you can get into charities.
You can get into raising money
because, you know, I've never
seen a hearse going down
the road that there's a Brink's
truck following them. Never.
...Wow.
...So you got to
make use of your money.
Take your money and make sure
you keep a piece aside for your
family, keep a piece aside
for the charities you want
and stuff like that.
But, you're not
taking it with ya.
You can have the biggest
casket in the world.
You can have whatever you want.
It means absolutely nothing.
...Awesome party, thank you.
>> Dianne: He may have been one
tough cop, but it's Jim's wife
Sandi who forces him to spend
some off duty time at
their Palm Springs getaway.
>> Jim: I say, live your life
to the fullest. Absolutely.
If I went out tomorrow,
I've had a great life.
I've been everywhere,
done as many things
as anybody else in the world has
done and I've been happy camper,
but, you know, I got a whole
bunch of other things
I want to do yet.
...Wouldn't mind getting...
>> Sandie: A little golf in.
>> Jim: A little golf in.
...Balanced life to me is having
enough time to get a golf game
in; to talk to my family and
spend some time with my wife.
[glasses clink]
>> Dianne: But don't expect Jim
to sit still for very long.
>> Jim: Retirement is something
I never even think about.
I hear guys talking about it,
I have very close friends
of mine say they're enjoying
their retirement.
I don't know what that is.
Maybe guys that retire
have a long day.
I have a very short day and
to me that's what I like,
what comes next I hope
there's some real
good deals out there.
'Cause I'm ready for 'em.
>> Jim: [softly] Yes.
>> Dianne: Coming up,
on the Year of The Dragons...
>> Arlene: I, I love it.
>> Dianne: Arlene Dickinson
leaves her comfort zone
to help out in the battle zone.
>> Arlene: Of all of the things
I've done in my life,
I would say this would be
the most meaningful thing
I've done in my life.
This week has been, um...
* [theme]
>> Dianne:
Welcome back to our special:
The Year of The Dragons,
our intimate look at
their lives outside the Den.
After six seasons in the Den,
Arlene Dickinson is known
as the formidable Dragon
with a tender side.
>> Arlene: This really
resonates with me.
Your story is amazing,
you are a hero, my friend.
I have a lot of
respect for firemen.
>> Kevin: Oh, cry me a river.
>> Arlene: Oh, shut up.
...I think I'm pretty
similar to who you see
on the television screen.
I am not an actress and
I don't know how to show up
any differently than what I am.
So what you hear me say is
really what I think and believe.
...I'd like to partner with you
not just make money off of you.
>> Wayne: I want to go
with Arlene.
>> Arlene: Yes, thank you.
Yeah, group hug, yeah.
>> Dianne: Outside the Den,
Arlene: Dickinson is one of
Canada's top marketers,
CEO of Venture Communications.
These days, her business prowess
propels her from the boardroom,
to the speaking circuit.
>> Arlene:
Today I was up at 5:00.
Getting my hair and makeup done.
And then I'm headed
to give a speech to about,
I think, 500 people.
And after I'm done that, I will
go from there right to the CBC
where I'll be taping from
I guess 11:00 till 8:00 tonight.
It's pretty typical of a day
but I, I love it.
>> Dianne: As the lone woman
in the Den, Arlene's been
asked to help inspire
this all-female audience.
>> Arlene: You guys the only
guys in this room?
>> Man: Yup.
>> Dianne: And although she's a
veteran TV star, she still gets
nervous about public speaking.
>> Arlene: If you're not
afraid every day.
If you're not a little bit
worried about whether what
you're doing is somewhat risky,
then I don't think
you're a true entrepreneur.
I think you wake up a little bit
afraid and a little bit excited
and a little bit hopeful and
a little bit fearful and
then you just go.
>> Woman: So,
without further ado,
please join me in welcoming
Arlene Dickinson!
>> Arlene: I thought I would
share with you today a little
bit about my story because
in the hopes that it might
help you understand
what my journey has been
and see if there's
some relevance in your lives
and journeys that you're on.
>> Dianne: Her specialty these
days? Nurturing and promoting
entrepreneurship.
During the past year,
Arlene spoke at more
than 100 conferences.
>> Arlene: You know, if you're
not getting up every day
and loving your job,
than why the heck
are you doing it?
You know, like it's...
[applause]
>> Arlene: I love it.
I love public speaking.
It takes a lot of energy,
I'm exhausted when I'm done
but I get a lot of energy back.
People are gracious,
they are attentive.
I always feel like
rewarded for sharing
and sometimes that feels
very selfish actually 'cause
I get a lot out of it.
I love it.
...Thank you very much.
[applause]
>> Gail: Hi, I'm Gail.
>> Arlene: Hi, Gail,
nice to meet you.
You know, people say,
how did you create success?
How did you do what you do?
And I keep saying, it's about
being honest, it's about being
authentic and when you do
that you can persuade people
to come along on your
life journey with you.
...Nice to me you.
>> Woman: Oh, my god.
>> Arlene: All right,
here we are.
>> Dianne: Arlene uses her
well-honed powers of persuasion
to help raise big money
for her favourite causes.
>> Arlene: Yeah.
Nice to see you again.
>> Man: Please welcome
both Arlene and Brian.
[applause]
>> Arlene: I've travelled
all over the world and I've
had the chance to see children
in horrible situations because
of the countries they live in
and because of the oppression
they live under.
We live in Canada.
It's unacceptable that any child
in our country is homeless.
[applause]
>> Dianne: Last year she helped
raise a million dollars through
Covenant House to benefit
homeless youth.
>> Man:
There's your bag, my dear.
>> Arlene: Thank you.
>> Dianne: She recruited
big wigs and celebrities...
>> Arlene: All right,
let's go find my bed.
>> Dianne: to sleep overnight
on the streets of Toronto.
It meant braving sub-zero
temperatures with some
cardboard, and a sleeping bag...
>> Arlene: Brian, say hello.
>> Brian: Oh, a day
in the life of Arlene?
>> Dianne: and bunking with
former Maple Leafs' General
Manger Brian Burke, and Toronto
Police chief Bill Blair.
>> Bill: Okay, let's talk
about hockey, what do you
think of the Leafs?
>> Arlene: Oooh.
I think that's why he is
a little moody. I never thought
I'd ever get to sleep with
the chief of police and the GM
of the Maple Leafs. I never
thought in my wildest dreams.
I'll let you know in the
morning who snores the most.
>> Brian: She could give
a woodpecker a headache,
she talks so much.
[Arlene laughs]
>> Arlene: That's what being
on the show's about for me.
It's about inspiring
people to do more,
it's about helping kids
realise their potential
in business and in life,
but I'd rather the attention was
on stuff like this than on me.
[airplane's engine rumbles]
>> Dianne:
What's closest to her heart?
The Canadian Forces.
Arlene has already made
two trips to Afghanistan
to boost morale.
>> Arlene: This week
has been, um...
Of all the things I've done in
my life, I would say this has
been the most meaningful
thing I've done in my life.
So, it's all been, uh,
pretty amazing.
I know I'm supposed
to shake hands.
But you know what,
we can do that anytime.
>> Dianne: For her service,
she was commissioned
honorary captain
in the Royal Canadian Navy.
> Man: You can copy this.
>> Arlene: Okay.
>> Man: Very good.
[all laughing]
>> Peter Mackay: So, it's
my great pleasure today
to officially announce
the appointment of
Arlene Dickinson
as the Honorary Captain
of the Royal Canadian Navy.
[applause]
>> Arlene: When I, uh,
came to Canada as an immigrant
many, many years ago
from South Africa, I never
thought I would be standing here
and be given the privilege
to do something for, um,
my country and for our country
that is of such significance.
So I am deeply honoured
and I'm deeply moved
by this opportunity.
I want to thank my Dad
for bringing me to Canada.
Um... [voice breaks]
[sobs] [applause]
...I cried. I did cry.
I cry because when I go back
to being raised as a child
who's an immigrant, who loves
this country fiercely and
I just knew my mom and dad
would be very proud of this.
Yeah, and I was. Yeah.
>> Man: And big smiles.
Beautiful.
Thank you very much.
* [upbeat Island]
>> Dianne: It's a busy pace,
yet once a year Arlene leaves
the spotlight to share some
sunlight with her family.
>> Arlene: Can you say
Hi to everybody?
>> Girl: Hi!
>> Arlene: I think the secret
to my success has been that
I am exactly the same person.
So I don't think about it as
a career, I just think about it
as something I do, it's just
one of the things that I am.
And I don't think about it
as far from being who I am?
How do you do that?
Sitting on a beach
for the rest of my life?
It, it sounds, it sounds
romantic for about 60 seconds
and then I go, uh, no.
I won't be doing that.
...Here's to happiness.
Cheers!
>> Dianne: Up next...
>> Man: David: Chilton.
>> Woman: David Chilton.
>> Man: David Chilton.
>> Dianne: David Chilton
might appear to lead
a fast-paced life...
>> David: Thank you. Thank you.
>> Dianne: but find out
how it's actually
low-tech, very low tech.
>> David: I use pen and paper.
I don't use any computer
technology at all.
It's true old-fashioned writing
and I can't write any other way.
* [theme]
>> Dianne: Back in the '80s,
when a young broker named
David Chilton put pen to paper,
he had no inkling he was
creating a multi-million
dollar publishing empire.
Or that he would become
a Dragon willing to
invest some big bucks.
>> Mary: Hand and Beak
is the first generation
of inter-species folk artists.
>> Dianne: This season,
he invested in a few fliers...
>> Mary: Luigi!
>> Dianne: like this one...
>> Mary: Oh, crap.
>> Dianne: greeting cards
made by a pet lovebird.
>> David: Yeah, I'll give you
what you want.
>> Kevin: Are you serious?
>> David: Yup.
[Kevin laughs]
>> Dianne: With his backing,
David made the deal soar.
>> Mary: Oh, Dave, thank you.
No other Dragon but a fellow
creative, imaginative weirdo
would ever have given me a deal.
* [serene]
>> Dianne: David has proved
he's a different kind of Dragon
but then again he's never been
your typical multi-millionaire.
>> David: Well, I was born
and raised in this area.
You know, I've never moved.
[KITCHEN-WATERLOO, ON.]
>> David: Love it.
>> Dianne: Home is Mennonite
country, near Waterloo, Ontario.
>> David: Yeah,
I actually quite like it
Because I'm a loner
to begin with and I like time
to think and be isolated.
Sometimes it's a little too
much, but in general it's been
well-suited to my lifestyle
and my approach to life.
>> Dianne: David lives alone in
this 1,300 square foot house
down a country road,
nestled between two farms.
>> David: Hey,
welcome to Dave Chilton's house,
nice to see you guys,
come on in.
The view is beautiful.
It really is.
It's on a side of a hill, the
rolling countryside is there.
It's got a great
four-season look.
It looks different at all the
different times of the year.
You can see forever because
you're, you're up high.
So the view is quite nice.
>> Dianne: The house is also
one of David's offices.
He writes every day using
the same table on which
he wrote The Wealthy Barber.
>> David: You can see the legs
no longer snap into place,
you have to set them up and
re-snap them all the time,
but the table's
held its own for 25 years.
I use pen and paper.
I don't use any computer
technology at all, I write
like this, I roll it up,
I throw it on the ground.
I clean it up at the end
of the day, I stroke it
out when I don't like.
It's true old-fashioned writing
and I can't write any other way.
>> Dianne: David has
another unusual quirk.
>> David: Well,
this is my kitchen.
And I'm really not sure
I've ever been in here before.
I'm a cookbook entrepreneur
that doesn't know
how to cook, I know,
it's embarrassing, isn't it?
It's not my thing at all.
In fact, it's fairly funny,
this is my almost
easy bake oven type thing.
I've used the stove top
three or four times.
I've never used the oven and
I wouldn't want to do that now,
it could explode. These are
my non-granite countertops,
they're a laminate of some sort.
>> Dianne: That means he eats
almost all his meals here at
the same small diner, ordering
the same dish every day.
>> David: The food is great.
I have a fairly strong routine
in the morning.
I have the same thing,
a couple of poached eggs,
some toast and a parfait and
a Diet Pepsi, can't start
the day without a Diet Pepsi.
But yeah, it's not a very
thrifty way to handle your funds
when you eat out this much.
And that being said,
I don't tend to eat in
really expensive places.
>> Waitress:
Great, see you tomorrow.
>> David: See you tomorrow.
>> Dianne: His personal routine
is rather unassuming and
so is his office space.
>> David: It's funny,
my office is above
a Tim Horton's, Domino's Pizza,
gas station in Kitchener.
Now, it's a lovely office,
but the location
is a little bit odd.
You have to walk through
the Tim Horton's drive-through
to get to the stairwell
to go up to the office.
>> Dianne: But David's real
office is almost everywhere
but Kitchener-Waterloo.
>> David: Hey, how are ya?
>> Man: Hi, good afternoon.
>> David: Checking in Chilton.
C-H-I-L-T-O-N.
>> Dianne: Last year he gave
more than a hundred speeches,
travelled 125,000 miles
and bedded down
in 200 different hotels.
No matter where he goes,
David always fills
a room to capacity.
>> Man: Please join me in
welcoming David Chilton.
>> David: Thank you, thank you.
...Love speaking.
You know of all the things I do,
I actually really
like everything I do.
I'm extremely lucky that way.
...When I first started out,
and even to a few years ago,
it's amazing how many people
wouldn't believe
that I was The Wealthy Barber.
I love listening to people
talk about books and covers
and business etcetera and
I'll go to the economics
business section and listen in.
And this couple in their late
30s, early 40s was looking
for a personal finance tome
for their teenage son.
And she finally said to him,
just get him a copy
of The Wealthy Barber.
And I was right there,
I was a yard away and
the husband said that guy
just said save 10 per cent and
you can retire when you're 35.
Well, I couldn't let that go,
I said, No, no.
He said save 10 per cent and
you can retire when you're 65,
not 35. 65.
He said, No...
[laughter]
No, he said 35. I read it.
And I said no, he said 65.
I wrote it.
[laughter]
I love my job, I'm excited
about going to work every day.
I like the new things
I'm working on. I mean,
I'm very, very lucky that way.
But of all the things I do,
speaking is by far my favourite.
>> Dianne: After he was tapped
to be the newest Dragon, David's
schedule went into overdrive.
>> Erin: In total we're
doing about 35 interviews.
>> David: Thirty-five?
>> Erin: Yeah.
>> David: That might be
a one-day record for me.
...Dave, nice to see you.
>> Dianne: On top of his regular
speaking gig...
>> Man: David Chilton,
The Wealthy Barber is here.
How are you?
>> David: I'm very well.
>> Lady: David Chilton,
the latest Dragon
on the season premiere...
>> Dianne: He became
the biggest get on every major
TV and radio show in Canada.
>> Melissa: He is here for the
first time on CP24 Breakfast,
David Chilton.
>> David: Thanks for having me.
>> Melissa: And your hair
is cut really nicely
as a Wealthy Barber.
>> David: It normally isn't,
by the way.
>> Melissa: Really?
>> David: No, honestly.
I'm on top of my game today.
...When you talk about being
a workaholic and I think that
it certainly carries a negative
connotation that what you've
done is you've emphasized work
and you've excluded other
things in your life and lost
track of what's important,
and had a poor balance.
...Erin, where are we going now?
>> Erin: The Edge, 102.1.
>> David: Oh, The Edge.
Good, I'm lookin'
forward to that one.
...I remember the one period
of about two years,
I didn't take a day off.
And I don't mean
I didn't take a holiday,
I didn't take a day off.
I didn't take a Sunday off,
I didn't take a day off,
because it was that crazy.
But you know, it was fun.
The funny thing is I look back
on that with fond memories.
Wrote it when I was 25,
it came out when I was 27.
I'm just very lucky it
took off and lead to a lot of
other good opportunities.
...For a long time
it was the top-selling
book but it looks
like 50 shades of Grey
was going to knock it off,
which is really upsetting.
>> Dan: Well, you know
what you should do...
>> David: Really upsetting.
>> Dean:
You should write a revision.
>> David: I am.
The Horny Barber.
[laughter]
>> Dianne: David made a career
preaching frugal living
but even he can indulge at his
private Costa Rican getaway.
[multiple birds chirping]
>> David: Isn't it beautifully
framed the way that looks?
Yeah, the designer
did a great job.
[water trickling]
...You know, if I lost
everything, like something
calamitous happened and I lost
it all, I think I would handle
it better than almost anybody
who had been through that.
I really do.
I'm not a money-oriented guy.
>> Dianne: This week he's
treating childhood buddies
to a golf vacation.
>> David: Woo! That's the
[bleep] I'm talking about.
Right there! Todd's first
good shot in a week.
Keep the cameras rolling,
rolling, rolling, rolling.
I don't define myself
by what I own at all.
...You guys want me to get
you one of these outfits?
And they can't take your
relationships away from you.
You've still got your friends,
you've still got your family.
It's fairly easy to be
upbeat and positive
when you've had a charmed life.
>> Lisa: What are we
looking for, David?
>> David: Todd's golf ball.
>> Lisa: Why?
>> David: Well, Todd has a...
he has an unusual
approach to golf.
>> Man: In what way?
>> David: He tries
to avoid the fairway.
...I think that, um,
you're successful in life
when you're happy.
I think that's actually the best
way to make money is to not
think about the money,
it's to think about how do I
help as many people as possible?
And you tend to do well
accidentally when you
take that approach.
That certainly
motivates me a lot.
...Woo!
>> Dianne: Coming up,
Bruce Croxon reveals
what it takes to stay on top.
>> Trainer: You getting tired?
>> Bruce: Yep.
>> Trainer: Too bad, keep going.
>> Dianne: And what he'd rather
do with his time...
>> Bruce: Okay, change it up.
Let's go.
...If you gave me a choice
about doing anything
on a Saturday, it'd be coach
son's hockey versus doing
just about anything else,
I'd take this.
* [theme]
>> Dianne: Welcome back,
we spent the last 12 months
trying very hard to keep up
with some of Canada's wealthiest
and busiest entrepreneurs,
our very own Dragons.
* [upbeat]
>> Dianne: For digital media
mogul Bruce Croxon, to stay
on top, you have to stay sharp.
>> Trainer: Five, four, three...
>> Arlene: So his day often
begins with a hardcore regimen.
[Bruce groans]
>> Trainer: Four more. Three.
>> Dianne: Boxing is also
the inspiration behind
his business's name:
Round13 Capital.
>> Bruce: Fraser-Ali, 1975,
The Thrilla in Manila.
And Round 13, was, you know,
what some say is the most brutal
round of history, or boxing
in the history of the sport.
>> Trainer: Woo!
There we go.
>> Bruce: And, uh, we built
this into a bit of a story
for entrepreneurs to say, look,
you know, the people we're
looking to back, in Round13,
are people that know how
to get off the stool.
>> Trainer: You getting tired?
>> Bruce: Yep.
>> Trainer: Too bad, keep going.
[Bruce laughs]
* [upbeat]
>> Bruce: Well, a typical day
for me starts pretty early,
uh, if I'm lucky, I've got
a work out in before I got
to get the kids out the door.
I've just dropped them off now,
and sure enough, I'm in danger
of being late again.
What the [bleeped] this guy.
I'm not stressed.
Calm, calm, calm.
Everything good,
as they say in Jamaica.
Everything fine.
>> Dianne: Headquarters for
Round13 Capital is in Toronto's
historic distillery district.
>> Bruce: Just pulling
into the Distillery.
Feels like my second home.
That's not a good thing.
On with the day!
>> Dianne: Before he heads to
his first of many meetings,
he pops by Balzac's Coffee,
one of his more high-profile
Dragons' Den investments.
>> Bruce: I'm really happy
we invested in this one,
because Diana,
she runs a great business.
You can see her brand
is all like; it's all
really well thought out.
I'll have a double latte
in a medium cup. Skim.
I've tried to stop coffee
a couple of times, for no good
reason, just to experiment.
I'm better off with it.
A lot better.
>> Dianne: Bruce's niche
is funding start-up internet
companies, which he does
from this small loft space.
>> Bruce: Sorry, I'm a bit late.
Running a bit behind.
...So the network security,
tell us a bit how
that business works.
...You know, in typical
entrepreneurial fashion,
Oh, this is easy.
You put a little bit of money
out, you back an entrepreneur,
and sit back and get rich.
It doesn't happen that way.
It's a discipline, um, and
I've learned that discipline.
I think I am a better investor
today, than when I left
Lavalife in mid 2006.
I've learned a lot of lessons
in the last 5 or 6 years.
And I'm getting ready
to go and do it again.
>> Dianne:
Bruce is a high-powered
venture capitalist...
>> Bruce: Room 10, let's go!
>> Dianne: but what you don't
know, he's also a full-time dad.
>> Bruce: Forwards, two things.
No dipsy doodling centre ice
to their blue line,
it's got to go in deep.
There's nothing wrong with a
shot on net from the blue line,
and then go for the rebound.
>> All: Let's go! Woo!
>> Bruce: I'm the only one of
the four that has little kids,
got out of the gate a little
late on the child rearing thing.
So I got two kids under ten.
It's a little more intense, then
probably some of the other guys,
it just means I don't
have the down time.
You know, I've got to make
the time count when I get it.
>> Referee: Goal!
[cheering]
>> Bruce: Okay, change it up,
let's go! Go get it, Lucas!
...If you gave me the choice
of doing anything midday
on a Saturday, if you gave me a
choice to coach my son's hockey,
versus doing just about
anything else, I'd take this.
You know, it's so much fun.
...To the net!
Ah, jeez that was close.
And I really enjoy it and
that goes for the ballet, too.
>> Dianne: Bruce uses his star
power to help save lives
by promoting a cause
close to his heart.
>> Bruce: Hi, how are you?
>> Dianne: So glad to see you.
>> Bruce: Good to see you.
>> Dianne:
You are all dressed up!
>> Bruce: Well,
it's a very important event!
>> Dianne: Bruce's
own children have allergies,
the kind that can be deadly.
>> Bruce: I've got two kids,
but with, uh, food allergies.
Yeah, absolutely. One guy
that's, like, off the chart
a lot of stuff.
>> Man: Is that right?
>> Bruce: Yeah.
>> Dianne: He's hosting
a lunch to raise money
for Anaphylaxis Canada.
[glass clinked]
>> Bruce: Oh, thank you,
everybody. The reason we're here
is because Debra and I have kids
with life-threatening
food allergies.
When you first find out
about this it is a bit
of a life-changer.
Things that our kids
can eat can kill them.
Debra and I are national
spokespeople, so we're not going
to miss a media opportunity,
so if you get tired of seeing
our mugs in the paper as it
relates to Anaphylaxis Canada,
too bad because that's
what we're going to do.
Um, and
it's a great opportunity.
>> Woman: We'd like to see
more of Debra, though.
>> Bruce: Yeah, I know.
[laughter]
>> Dianne: Even his fellow
Dragons have come out
to support the cause.
>> Bruce: Chilly drove
two and a half hours.
Arlene is insanely busy,
so that's pretty amazing, right,
that you can get that kind
of support for something
that you're trying to do.
...Good to have you,
and it was appreciated!
>> Arlene: Yeah.
>> Dianne: Bruce: knows how to
work a room, which is why he's
now a sought-after speaker...
>> Man: How are you doing?
>> Bruce: Good. Good
>> Dianne: and an inspiration
for some of Canada's
youngest entrepreneurs.
>> Bruce: You know the number
of people that say they watch
the show with their kids is
one of the biggest surprises.
>> Fan:
One more, one more. Sorry!
>> Bruce: It's okay.
>> Woman: Ready?
>> Man: Please welcome
to the stage, Bruce Croxon.
[applause]
>> Dianne: He's here to share
his experience about building
an Internet empire from
scratch and he's got
the scars to prove it.
>> Bruce: Life of
an entrepreneur, dot, dot, dot
not for everyone.
[laughter]
You know, you won't ever hear me
taking a shot at somebody
that goes to work every day,
collects a pay cheque and then
skis, mountain bikes, surfs,
has hobbies and lives
a balanced lifestyle.
I've actually have often
been envious of it.
[laughter]
...Be prepared to work
very, very hard. You know,
be prepared to have whatever
it is you're choosing to do...
pretty much take over your life.
* [upbeat]
>> Dianne: Bruce can and does
escape e-mail and phone calls
by chartering a small plane and
flying due north of Toronto.
He owns a breathtaking
eight-acre island
on Georgian Bay.
>> Bruce: When I've accomplished
something, or hit a milestone,
or I feel like I've earned
a break, I take a break.
...Let's start; let's start
at the far southern end, right?
And we'll take it from there.
>> Dianne: With the help of two
architects, he's commissioning
an eco-friendly family getaway
that needs no electricity.
>> Bruce: And remember as
I was saying, right, the views
to the east are unbelievable.
Right?
So the sun comes up, right?
...I've flown the architects up
today to really walk the island,
get a feel for what I'm feeling.
...In the original discussion
we talked about replacing
the windows, right?
I don't know, you know,
I mean, it's pretty sweet.
...My lesson for an entrepreneur
is look, you know, you're going
to have to work very hard.
Especially today to make it as
an entrepreneur, but what's your
little patch of solitude or
the place you recharge, because
you can't go your entire life.
I've met a few of those guys
but not many, right?
You lose perspective,
you get burnt out, you know.
Your, your friendships suffer,
your kids suffer.
You need a place to recharge.
You know, this just
happens to be mine.
Can I imagine a time when
I'm not going to be working?
You know, characteristic
of an entrepreneur
is that they're always noodling,
always thinking.
I can't imagine a time when
I won't be thinking of new
ideas and things that the world
needs that it doesn't have.
So to the extent that
that's work, I'll be working.
[water laps the shoreline]
* [theme]
>> Dianne: After the break...
>> Kevin:
We're having a good day?
>> Man:
We're having a good start.
>> Dianne: Find out what it's
like to work for Kevin O'Leary.
>> Lady: Is it scary
To give Kevin bad news?
[Kevin laughs]
>> Kevin: If you can't make it,
I'm gonna shoot ya.
>> Dianne: And how success
almost cost him everything.
>> Kevin:
I realised this is hollow.
And look at the damage
I'm doing to my family.
Oh.. it hurts.
* [theme]
>> Dianne: It might come
as no surprise to you
that Kevin O'Leary loves
to begin the day already
taking down his competition.
>> Kevin: All right, here we go.
>> Dianne: It's the crack of
dawn, and already Kevin is
getting deals done on the court.
>> Kevin: Three times a week
I play squash at 6:10
with a bond trader.
Bond traders are the only
other guys awake at that hour.
Bond traders are the smartest
money, they get up the earliest.
As a result, they're like me,
they want to know what's
going on around the world.
* [upbeat]
>> Kevin: Bond traders tend
to be pudgy guys so they're
easy to beat in squash.
>> Dianne: Turns out, this
trader isn't such a pushover.
>> Kevin: Ugh. Brutal.
>> Dianne: But there's
no time to cool off.
>> Woman: Hey, Kevin.
>> Kevin: Yeah.
...What's next is
I have to do a television
broadcast with Heather.
>> Dianne: Today's topic?
The 25th anniversary of
the Free Trade Agreement.
>> Heather: Good or bad
for Canada? Kevin.
>> Kevin: I think it's been
absolutely terrific for Canada.
We have tremendous need
for capital in this country.
...There's no such thing
as time off.
Stuff's happening 24/7.
But you can integrate your life,
your family, your work,
all together.
It's a perfect flow.
[horns blaring]
>> Dianne: Getting two jobs done
before 6:00 in the morning,
seven days a week, is routine.
>> Kevin: I used to drive,
but now I take a limo.
I can't work when I'm driving
myself; I can't really
have a good communication
or on a conference call.
If I'm sitting in the back
of a limousine, I can.
I even broadcast using
high speed internet sticks
from the back of limos,
anywhere in North America,
I've even done it from Europe.
Each waking moment, I have to
decide, is this a TV moment?
Or is this a money moment?
>> Amanda: Welcome to
The Lang & O'Leary Exchange.
I'm Amanda Lang.
>> Kevin: And I'm Kevin O'Leary.
...This is a fantastic idea
there is no question about it.
So, how does it look today?
>> Woman: Right there.
Turn your face straight
on towards me? Excellent.
>> Dianne: To keep on schedule,
Kevin relies on his assistant
Nancy who divvies up his day
into 15-minute blocks,
right up to 11:00 pm.
>> Nancy: After Lang/O'Leary
you have the tasting event
and then after that
I'll have the car take you
to another dinner event.
>> Kevin: Okay.
* [smooth Jazz]
>> Kevin: And on Friday
we're going to Boston, right?
>> Nancy: Yes, which means
you're probably going to have to
leave at 5:00 a.m. that morning.
>> Kevin: Oh, that's brutal.
>> Nancy: Yeah.
>> Kevin: When I look at the
map, on Tuesday night, and I see
anything in there that I change
my mind about, I'll call Nancy
at 2:00 in the morning and
say, hey, hey, blow that off.
And you know what's
beautiful about it?
It's my decision.
Nobody can change that.
I don't work for anybody.
>> Dianne: But a lot
of people work for Kevin,
which means regular visits
to O'Leary Fund headquarters.
* [upbeat]
>> Kevin: Rick, do you want
to show us what you're doing?
>> Rick: Sure.
>> Kevin: Okay.
>> Dianne: Believe it or not,
Kevin can be a nice boss.
>> Kevin: Rick does bonds.
I love bonds.
>> Rick: Overall,
a pretty good day, a pretty
good start to the market.
>> Kevin: And I'm making
money right now.
>> Rick: Exactly.
>> Kevin: That's the part
I love the best.
We're having a good day.
>> Rick: We're having
a good start, yeah.
>> Is it scary to give
Kevin bad news?
[Kevin laughs]
>> Rick: A little bit, I guess.
>> Kevin: What I love about it
is I get to hire really
smart young people,
that are ambitious, that want
to grow with the firm.
That want it to be bigger,
they want to be successful too.
>> Brenner: Hi, Matt, this is
Brenner from O'Leary Funds.
How are you?
>> Dianne: Kevin: is a
'not-so-nice' boss when his
sales people come up short.
>> Brenner: It will be a good
time just to sit on and, uh,
a nice conservative product.
>> Kevin: We've got to win.
We have to generate sales
and if you can't make it,
I'm gonna shoot you.
>> Dianne: It's no wonder.
Kevin leads by example.
>> Man: Just with
a little bit of an angle.
>> Dianne: Between meetings he
fits in a magazine photo shoot,
a radio interview...
>> Kevin: I keep telling
young people today, don't go
in debt to buy real estate,
R-E-N-T, that's your future.
>> Dianne: and a hit for his
nightly business program on CBC.
>> Kevin: All right,
time for Lang & O'Leary.
I love sales,
I believe it's in my genes
from my heritage, you know.
I'm a Phoenician-Lebanese-Irish
guy and all those people sell
all the time, they always were.
They were cruising around
the Mediterranean selling
blue dye to everybody else.
[Crowd cheers]
[Kevin laughs]
>> Kevin: All right!
>> Dianne: Kevin now uses
his name to sell many things,
not just mutual funds.
Today, in Toronto,
he's launching O'Leary Wines.
>> Kevin: Part of sales
is entertaining...
...Oh, the O'Leary is good.
[laughter]
>> Woman: Are your wines
as bold as you are?
>> Kevin: Ha, ha,
this is good stuff.
...Because if they're not
listening to you, you're not
going to sell them anything.
...Did you get red and white,
or just red?
>> Woman: Just the white.
>> Kevin: A lot of people don't
know how good Ontario wines are
and I thought I'd get behind it
and bring out some wines,
at a great value. These are
tremendous value wines.
>> Man: I like your no nonsense
approach to everything.
>> Kevin: I appreciate that.
I have a lot of fun
with it, let me tell you.
...It's a consistent with
what I am all about.
Everybody knows I love good
wine, it's part of my brand.
I don't put my name
on things I don't love and
use myself, or drink or eat.
So, I'm very proud of this.
And this is just the first two.
>> Dianne: Being a CEO, a star,
and a Dragon meant Kevin was
always on the road and up until
the wee hours of the night.
>> Kevin: Hi, there.
>> Dianne: He travelled
constantly to promote
his first book...
>> Woman: You're good?
>> Dianne: and put the final
touches on his second book
about financial advice.
>> Woman:
That's great, I love it.
>> Dianne: It wasn't long
until Kevin's high-speed life
came crashing down.
>> Woman: Hair,
lovely, gorgeous.
Little tiny bit
happier than that.
>> Kevin: I'm 57, and just went
through a really unusual year.
You know, I separated
from my wife for a year,
lived like a mad man.
I mean, I just, you know,
went crazy. I think what
happened to me there was I think
I let celebrity get to me.
I jetted to San Tropez,
I did all the crazy stuff.
And I realised this is hollow.
This is really dumb.
And look at the damage
I'm doing to my family.
[soft sniffle]
[hard sniffle]
>> Dianne: Kevin
now stays closer to home
or his cottage in Muskoka.
>> Kevin: Well, thanks,
I'm soaked, that's great.
[Kevin chuckles]
Ah, it's rough day at
the office, that's great.
So what are we having for lunch?
>> Linda: We're having
hamburgers and hotdogs.
>> Kevin: My classic,
that's wonderful.
>> Linda: Yeah.
>> Kevin: Trevor, let's go
upstairs and get some lunch.
...I really, really
value every day.
...It's the first year I'm
realising, wow, I am definitely
more than half-cooked.
...You know,
it's a huge debate.
Which is better?
a hamburgers or a hotdog?
>> Linda: But the worst
for you is the bun.
>> Kevin: That's why we're
not eating buns today, we're
going to eat them in lettuce.
I'm going to be snuff city
one day. So I've got to decide
what I want to do with
the rest of my time.
...The minimum commitment
was 2 million on that and
he only got 2 million 4.
>> Dianne: He may still
work 'round the clock,
but he's learned to strike
the right balance.
>> Kevin: I'm going to
figure it out that way,
that way we can expense
the whole thing annually.
...I don't make the same mistake
twice and I think that's key,
I think everybody has
to learn that way.
But don't waste time,
always follow your gut,
never second guess yourself,
that is useless and I think
at the end of the day if you do
that, you can really enjoy
your life and you can be free.
Free to do whatever you like.
* [upbeat]
>> George: One in 10 Canadians
is watching Dragons' Den
every week, that is
amazing accomplishment,
1 in 10 Canadians.
How about a hand
for the Dragons
and the whole team!
>> Dianne: It's been a busy and
profitable year for the Dragons.
But perhaps the biggest
payoff came just recently.
>> George: Bruce is here.
>> Dianne: The Chamber of
Commerce declared Sept 19th
Dragons' Den Day in Canada for
fostering a spirit of innovation
throughout the country.
>> Bruce: Because we're
optimists, us entrepreneurs.
You know, we're, we're,
yes, it can be done people.
>> George:
Hello, Arlene Dickinson.
Come on, Arlene.
>> Dianne: More than a thousand
entrepreneurs have entered
the Den and faced the Dragons .
>> Arlene: Being a Dragon
is a full-time job.
People might think it's just
television, it's so much
more than television.
And that's why I think
I love it so much.
>> George: Kevin O'Leary!
>> Kevin: The definition of
an entrepreneur is someone
that puts freedom on top
of all other aspirations.
It's providing you freedom
and your family freedom
and anybody else you want
to give freedom to.
That's power.
>> George: Jim Treliving!
>> Jim: I get people
stopping me in the street
that are 10 years old.
I think what it teaches them
that there's a world out there
that is completely different
to their world and
it opens their mind.
>> George: Please welcome
my friend, Dave Chilton.
>> David: Dragons' Den
is a huge hit. Like,
when you're here you see
the pride and passion
that people have.
>> Dianne: What's clear about
the turnout? Dragons' Den
is helping transform Canada
into a nation of entrepreneurs.
>> Jim: I think Dragons' Den
is probably the best thing that
ever happened in this country.
>> George:
Dragons' Den Day in Canada!
[crowd cheers]
>> Bruce:
That scared the heck out of me!