>> Anthony: TONIGHT POLICE
CONFIRM A SEXUAL ASSAULT
INVESTIGATION THAT GOES FROM
St. JOHNS TO GANDER WITH A
CONNECTION TO LAST WEEKEND'S
SCI-FI CONVENTION.
>> Debbie: PEOPLE IN MARYSTOWN
DON'T WANT THIS IN THIS
NEIGHBOURHOOD.
THEY WANT DEVELOPERS TO STOP
THE DEVELOPMENT.
>> Anthony: SHOWING OFF IN
NATURE.
A PHOTO CONTEST GETS PEOPLE
OUTSIDE DURING SOME OF OUR COLD
SPRING WEATHER.
>> THERE'S NO SUCH THING AS BAD
WEATHER, JUST INAPPROPRIATE
CLOTHING.
>> Ryan: YOU WILL NEED TO
BUNDLE UP IF YOU ARE ALONG THE
COASTLINE.
TOMORROW SEA BREEZE SETTING UP.
A TASTE OF SUN FOR EVERYONE
TOMORROW AND ESPECIALLY SUNDAY
ACROSS THE ISLAND.
THE DETAILS ARE COMING UP.
>> Anthony: THANKS, RYAN.
WELCOME TO "HERE AND NOW", I'M
ANTHONY GERMAIN.
>> Debbie: AND I'M DEBBIE
COOPER.
ONE GIRL'S WEEKEND STARTED AT A
SCI-FI CONVENTION AND ENDED
WITH A SEXUAL ASSAULT
INVESTIGATION.
IT BEGINS AT THE HOLIDAY INN IN
St. JOHNS.
THAT'S WHERE KRISSY HOLMES IS.
SHE JOINS US LIVE WITH THE
DETAILS.
>> Krissy: THIS TIME LAST WEEK
THERE WERE HUNDREDS AT THE
HOLIDAY INN IN St. JOHNS FOR
THE SCI-FI ON THE ROCK
CONVENTION.
SATURDAY THE 14-YEAR-OLD GIRL
AT THE CENTRE OF THIS STORY WAS
AT THE CONVENTION.
AND SOMEHOW LATER THAT DAY SHE
ARRIVED IN GANDER, WHICH IS
WHERE THE SEXUAL ASSAULT IS
SAID TO HAVE TAKEN PLACE.
POLICE CONFIRMED THE INCIDENT
DID OCCUR OVER A SATURDAY,
SUNDAY PERIOD, THE GIRL ARRIVED
IN St. JOHNS.
THERE HAVE BEEN SEVERAL REPORTS
THAT HAVE CHARACTERIZED THIS AS
AN ABDUCTION BUT AFTER SPEAKING
TO THE R.N.C. AND RCMP, NEITHER
ARE ABLE TO LABEL IT THAT AT
THIS POINT.
THEY ARE INVESTIGATING A
COMPLAINT INTO A SEXUAL ASSAULT
AND RIGHT NOW THEY ARE JUST
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT HOW THAT
GIRL ENDED UP IN GANDER.
WHAT THEY ARE DOING RIGHT NOW,
THEY ARE TRYING TO CORROBORATE
THIS STORY, THEY ARE
INTERVIEWING WITNESSES AND
TRYING TO FIND OUT WHAT'S WHAT.
THEY SAY THEY AREN'T WILLING TO
RELEASE DETAILS BUT WE ARE
EXPECTING SOMETHING NEW COMING
UP NEXT WEEK.
LIVE FOR "HERE AND NOW" I'M
KRISSY HOLMES IN St. JOHNS.
>> Anthony: SENIORS IN
MARYSTOWN ARE A AGAINST A
DEVELOPMENT IN THEIR TOWN.
OLDER RESIDENTS SAY THEY ARE
WORRIED ABOUT THEIR SAFETY.
>> GOING TO SAY WE ARE PUTTING
FOUR GIRLS, WHAT WILL HAPPEN IN
FOUR YEARS OR SIX YEARS' TIME.
WE COULD HAVE HARDENED
CRIMINALS OR ANYONE LIVING NEXT
TO US.
>> Debbie: LOVELY SUNNY DAY
TODAY.
>> Ryan: THAT'S RIGHT.
DEPENDING ON WHERE YOU WERE.
HAVE A LOOK AT THE TEMPERATURE
CONTRAST.
20° IN BADGER.
4° BONAVISTA.
WE HAVE A COUPLE SHOWERS
POPPING UP.
WE WILL ZOOM IN AND SEE IF YOU
ARE HEADED OUT THE DOOR IN THE
NEXT FEW MINUTES KEEP THE
UMBRELLA HANDY.
THERE ARE SOME SCATTERED
SHOWERS WORKING TOWARD THE
GRAND FALLS WINDSOR AREA.
THAT'S WHERE YOUR RISK OF
SHOWERS IS.
SOME FOG PATCHES SETTING UP.
DRY HERE IN THE EAST.
WE ARE LOOKING AT CLEARING
CONDITIONS IN LABRADOR.
YOUR TOMORROW FORECAST AND
BEYOND IN A FEW MINUTES.
DEBBIE?
>> Debbie: THANKS, RYAN.
THE ICE CAPS HAVE TAKEN A
COMMANDING 3-1 LEAD IN THEIR
SEMIFINAL SERIES WITH WILKES
BURY SCRANTON PENGUINS.
THEY ARE ONE WIN AWAY FROM
ADVANCING TO THE FINAL.
THEY WERE FIRST ON THE BOARD
AND THEY SCORED LATE IN THE
SECOND PERIOD ON A POWER-PLAY
GOAL BY WILL O'NEILL ON A
FIVE-ON-THREE ADVANTAGE.
NOW THE PENGUINS TIED THE GAME
AT 1-1 IN THE THIRD AS BRIAN'S
SHOT HIT OFF CAPS BRENDAN'S
HEAL AND GOT PAST MICHAEL
HUTCHINSON.
THE ICE CAPS WINNER WILL COME
ON THE POWER PLAY AT 9:19 OF
THE THIRD.
JOSH LUNDEN SCORED HIS FIRST
GOAL OF THE PLAYOFFS AS HE
POKED THE WRAPAROUND INTO THE
NET.
MICHAEL HUTCHINSON CAME UP WITH
17 SAVES TO WIN THE GAME.
GAME FIVE IS TOMORROW NIGHT IN
SCRANTON AT 8:30 ISLAND TIME.
>> AND STILL WITH HOCKEY AFTER
GAME FIVE, COMBINED 11 GOALS,
GAME SIX WAS THE POLAR OPPOSITE
FOR THE CANADIENS AND RANGERS.
YOUNG DUSTIN TOKARSKI WAS
SENSATIONAL.
IN THE THIRD AS THEY TRIED TO
STEAL IT.
31 SAVES ON THE NIGHT FOR THE
24-YEAR-OLD.
AT THE OTHER END, PERSPECTION.
HENRIK LUNDQVIST DENIES ALL 18
SHOTS INCLUDING ONE YOU WILL
SEE ON HIGHLIGHT REELS FOR A
VERY LONG TIME.
DOMENIC MOORE.
1-0.
NEW YORK WAITS FOR THE WINNER
OF THE KINGS BLACKHAWKS SERIES.
>> Debbie: NOW NEWS FROM THE
COURTS, CONVICTED KILLER KENNY
GREEN WILL SPEND A FEW EXTRA
DAYS IN PRISON.
TODAY HE PLEADED GUILTY TO
BREACHING A BAIL CONDITION AND
WAS SENTENCED FOR TEN DAYS.
HE WASN'T SUPPOSED TO BE IN ANY
ESTABLISHMENT THAT SERVES
ALCOHOL.
GREEN WAS SENTENCED TWO WEEKS
AGO FOR SIX YEARS FOR THE
BEATING DEATH OF JOEY WHALEN.
>> Anthony: TODAY WAS ALSO A
COURT DATE FOR FIVE GUYS
ACCUSED OF ATTACKING GREEN.
ONE OF THEM, JUSTIN HARVEY HAS
ELECTED TRIAL.
THE OTHER CO ACCUSED PHILIP PIN
AND JUSTIN WISE MAN HAVE NO
CHOICE BUT TO GO THAT ROUTE AS
WELL.
>> ST. JOHNS MOB BABY.1Gz;
>> THE CHILLY WEATHER ISN'T
STOPPING THESE FOLKS FROM
GETTING OUTSIDE.
*
MEET DAPHNE KING THE WOMAN WHO
RESCUED THESE DUCKS AND GAVE
MOUTH TO BEAK RESUSCITATION TO
SAVE A LIFE.
>> Debbie: WELCOME BACK.
IF YOU OWN A CELL PHONE YOU
HAVE PROBABLY TAKEN A SELFIE
NOW ONE GROUP IS USING THE
SELFIE TO ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO
GET OUTSIDE.
>> SPRING WAERNLG, LET'S JUST
SAY IT'S UNPREDICTABLE.
ONE DAY THERE'S SNOWFLAKES, THE
NEXT THERE'S NOT A CLOUD IN THE
SKY.
>> I LIKE TO PLAY IN MY
TREEHOUSE IN THE BACKYARD AND
SWING IN MY SBING.
SWING.
>> TODAY MAY BE A PERFECT DAY
BUT NOT EVERYDAY THIS MONTH HAS
BEEN LIKE THIS.
THIS MONTH THEY ENCOURAGE
PEOPLE TO GET OUT, BUNDLE UP
AND TAKE IN FRESH AIR NO MATTER
WHAT THE WEATHER.
>> IT'S TO ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO
GET OUTSIDE.
RECONNECT WITH NATURE.
IT'S NOT TO BE ACTIVE BUT YOU
COULD SIT OUT ON YOUR LAWN
CHAIR AND READ YOUR BOOK.
>> EVERY TIME PEOPLE WERE
OUTSIDE THEY TOOK NATURE
SELFIES.
SO FAR 222 ADVENTURES ACROSS
THE PROVINCE, POSTED THEMSELVES
IN THE GREAT OUTDOORS.6+l&
>> PEOPLE WHO HAVE BEEN POSTING
ABOUT WHAT THEY HAVE BEEN DOING
IT'S BEEN REALLY NEAT TO SEE
THEM SHARE THEIR STORIES AND
THEN OTHER PEOPLE WILL RESPOND
BY SAYING WOW I'VE NEVER BEEN
THERE BEFORE, CAN YOU TELL ME
HOW TO GET THERE.
>> NOW MAY WASN'T THE MOST
MOTIVATIONAL MONTH.
THE WEATHER WAS TERRIBLE.
BUT STEPPING OUT INTO THE COLD
HAS IT'S BENEFITS.
>> BUT I THINK ONE OF THE BEST
THINGS WAS JUST THE CLARITY OF
MIND TO GET OUTSIDE AND THINGS
THAT SEEMED REALLY STRESSFUL
BEFORE DIDN'T SEEM TO MATTER AS
MUCH AND JUST TO BE OUTSIDE AND
GET A BIT OF EXERCISE.
>> THE WEATHER IS SUPPOSED TO
BE SUNNY TOMORROW BUT THAT
ISN'T STOPPING THIS GROUP FROM
SEEKING OUT A CHILL.
THE CHALLENGE A GROUP ICEBERG
TRIP ON BLACK WOOD TRAIL.
SALIMA PUNJAMI, CBC NEWS,
TOPTAIL BEACH.
>> POWER OF POSITIVE THINKING
WHEN IT COMES TO OUR WEATHER.
>> Ryan: IT WORKS, TO A DEGREE.
THAT WAS THE WORDING I WAS
LOOKING FOR.
TOMORROW WON'T BE TOO BAD OF A
DAY.
A LITTLE BIT COOLER ALONG PARTS
OF THE COAST.
THAT SEA BREEZE WILL SET UP.
IF YOU ARE ALONG THE EAST COAST
TRAIL, PACK THE SWEATER IT
NEEDS TO BE A LITTLE COOL.
BUT INLAND CONDITIONS, CENTRAL
INLAND, MID TO HIGH TEENS.
WEATHER ON THE WAY HEADLINES.
THE FIRST ONE WE WILL BE
LOOKING AT, PRETTY DECENT
LOOKING SATURDAY.
WE WILL CALL IT A SOLID
SATURDAY.
A MIX OF SUN IN THE MIX FOR
SUNDAY.
21° THE HIGH IN BADGER, 23 THE
HIGH IN CORNER BROOK.
COOLER TODAY IN LABRADOR BEHIND
THE FRONT SINKING SOUTH.
THE CLOUD COVER HAS BEEN PRETTY
DOMINANT.
AS YOU TAKE A LOOK AT THE WINDS
THEY HAVE BEEN ALL VARIABLE.
WINDS HAVE BEEN FAIRLY LIGHT IN
LABRADOR.
THERE ARE THOSE SHOWERS THAT
HAVE BEEN POPPING UP WEST OF
CENTRAL NEWFOUNDLAND.
HEADS UP IF YOU ARE HEADED OUT
THE DOOR.
THE BULK OF THE ACTIVITY SOUTH,
IT'S BEEN A NICE CLEARING DAY.
THIS TROUGH KIND OF STALLING
OUT ENOUGH TO KICK CLOUD COVER
THROUGH YOUR SATURDAY AND A
SLIGHT CHANCE OF A SHOWER ALONG
THAT FRONT TOMORROW.
MAINLY INTO THE INTERIOR,
CENTRAL AND NORTHEAST COAST
COULD SEE AN AFTERNOON SPRINKLE.
DO KEEP THAT IN MIND AND IT
WILL KICK SOME CLOUD COVER UP.
EXPECT THE CLOUD COVER TO
DOMINATE AT TIMES TOMORROW
THROUGH EASTERN PARTS OF
NEWFOUNDLAND AND ACROSS THROUGH
CENTRAL.
SHOULD GET 12-15 IN THROUGH
EASTERN PARTS OF NEWFOUNDLAND.
SO SOUTH, SOUTHEASTERLY WINDS.
PLACES LIKE FERRYLAND EXPOSED
TO THE ON SHORE FLOW.RAñ
A BIT OF A SOUTH, SOUTHEAST
WIND.
CLOUD COVER THICKENS UP.
A PRETTY SOLID DAY.7YFq
TEMPERATURES IN THE 7-9° RANGE.
AND HOW ABOUT THE INTERIOR
LABRADOR.
YOU HAVE A CHANCE OF AN A.M.
FLURRY WITH FREEZING DRIZZLE.
NAIN MAKKOVIK, WINDS LIGHT
THERE.
YOUR 7-DAY FORECAST, SUNDAY
INTO NEXT WEEK, COMING UP.
MR. COLEMAN, IF HE REALLY
WANTED THE JOB SHOULD BE IN
THAT OFFICE TODAY.
>> Anthony: SOME STRONG WORDS
FROM THE FORMER PREMIER TO THE
SOON TO BE PREMIER.
>> Anthony: IN JUST FIVE WEEKS
FRANK COLEMAN BECOMES LEADER OF
THE P.C. PARTY AND THEN PREMIER
OF THE PROVINCE.
ROGER GRIMES IS A GUEST ON THIS
WEEK'S "ON POINT" HERE IS SOME
OF WHAT HE HAD TO SAY.
>> ALL THAT'S HAPPENING HERE IS
THE SHAM THAT THE P.C. PARTY IS
CURRENTLY PERPETRATING
SUGGESTING THERE'S A LEADERSHIP
RACE WHEN IT DOESN'T EXIST, MR.
COLEMAN IF HE REALLY WANTED THE
JOB SHOULD BE IN THAT OFFICE
TODAY.
THERE'S NO REASON FOR THEM TO
WAIT ANOTHER FIVE WEEKS.
NOW HE IS GIVING DIRECTION
OBVIOUSLY TO THE CURRENT
PREMIER.
THE PREMIER OF THE PROVINCE IS
TAKING DIRECTION FROM A PRIVATE
CITIZEN AND HAVING THAT PRIVATE
CITIZEN'S STAFF PEOPLE PAID FOR
BY PRIVATE TAX PAYERS LIKE ME
INSTEAD OF BY THE P.C. PARTY OR
MR. COLEMAN PERSONALLY.
>> DOESN'T IT MAKE SENSE MR.
COLEMAN WOULD BRING HIS OWN
STAFF IN AND IF THEY CAN STOP
HAVING A COUPLE WEEKS TO GET UP
TO SPEED THAT MAKES MORE SENSE
THAN HAVING THEM GO IN ONE DAY
AND FLIPPING A SWITCH.
>> I DON'T BUY IT.
IF MR. COLEMAN WANTS TO GET UP
TO SPEED, HE HAS BEEN DEFECTO.
THE PREMIER OF THIS PROVINCE
FOR A MONTH.
HE SEEMS LIKE A RELUCTANT BRIDE
TO ME.
HE DOESN'T SEEM TO REALLY WANT
THE JOB.
LIKE THE DOG CHASING THE CAR,
HE JUST GOT THE CAR, BUT HE IS
AFRAID TO TAKE THE CAR.
TAKE IT OVER, BRING IN YOUR
PEOPLE, GET ON WITH THE JOB.
HE IS SUPPOSED TO BE A BRIGHT
SMART INTELLIGENT, FOCUSED
ENERGETIC, SINCERE PERSON, GET
IN AND SHOW THE PEOPLE OF THE
PROVINCE LIKE.
>> UNLIKE MANY PEOPLE WHO TAKE
OVER THE CHAIR, HE IS NEW TO
POLITICS.
HE ADMITS HE IS A POLITICAL
NEWBIE.
DOESN'T IT MAKE SENSE FOR HIM
TO TAKE A FEW MONTHS TO GET UP
TO SPEED.
>> YES, THERE IS SOME CREDIT
AND MERIT TO THAT ARGUMENT.
BUT NOT TO HAVE HIS PAID
ORGANIZERS THAT HE HAD ON HIS
STAFF FOR A LEADERSHIP CAMPAIGN
THAT NO LONGER EXISTS.
AND THAT'S THE ONLY REASON HE
IS NOT TAKING THE OFFICE, HE
SAID I REALLY CAN'T BECAUSE THE
LEADERSHIP ISN'T OVER UNTIL
JULY.
WHAT A PILE OF NONSENSE THAT IS.
THIS HAS BEEN HIS JOB SINCE
BILL BARRY QUIT.
HE KNOWS HE HAS IT.
IF HE WANTS TO TAKE PEOPLE OFF
HIS PAYROLL AND PUT THEM ON MY
PAYROLL AND YOUR PAYROLL, GO
SIT IN THE CHAIR.
>> Debbie: FROM POLITICS TO A
STORY ABOUT YOUR HEALTH.
MORE THAN $3 BILLION PEOPLE
AROUND THE WORLD DON'T GET
ENOUGH IRON IN THEIR DIET.
MANY OF THEM CAN'T AFFORD
COSTLY SUPPLEMENTS.
NOW A CANADIAN COMPANY IS
TRYING TO CHANGE THAT.
IT'S SLOGAN, A FISH IN EVERY
POT.
BUT IT'S NOT THE KIND OF FISH
YOU WOULD THINK.
KIM BRUNHUBER EXPLAINS.
>> BUBBLING AWAY AT THE BOTTOM
OF A POT IT LOOKS MORE LIKE AN
ORNAMENT THAN A  NUTRIENT.
IF YOU PUT A PIECE OF IRON INTO
THE POT THE METAL WILL LEACH
INTO THE FOOD.
WHAT IF IT WAS IN THE SHAPE OF
SOMETHING CONSIDERED LUCKY,
LIKE A FISH.
>> YOU JUST PUT IT IN THE POT.
ADD A LITTLE CITRUS TO HELP THE
IRON LEACH.
>> IT'S MADE OF RECYCLED
MATERIALS, COSTS $5 AND IS
EXPECTED TO LAST FIVE YEARS.
THEIR GOAL THIS YEAR EXPAND
FROM THE 1,000 FISH Q-;CBEING USED
NOW TO 10,000 IN SEVERAL
DIFFERENT COUNTRIES.
GAVIN ARMSTRONG JUST GOT BACK
FROM CAMBODIA TO SEE IF A YEAR
AFTER THE.
>> DR. STANLEY HELPED DESIGN A
DIFFERENT KIND OF IRON
SUPPLEMENT.
HE LIKES IT BUT IT'S NOT
PERFECT HE SAYS.
>> THE NICE THING ABOUT IT, I
THINK PEOPLE WILL USE IT.
THE PROBLEMATIC, I THINK IT'S
STILL EARLY DAYS AND I THINK
MORE RESEARCH HAS TO BE DONE.
>> IT'S CEO'S SAY IT DOES SHOW
IT WORKS AND IS PLANNING TO USE
GOVERNMENT FUNDING FOR FURTHER
RESEARCH.
>> I BELIEVE ONCE WE HAVE THOSE
GOVERNMENT RESULTS WE WILL HAVE
THAT BUY-IN, BECAUSE THIS IS A
CHEAPER ALTERNATIVE TO
DISTRIBUTING IRON PILLS THAT
AREN'T BEING USED.
>> DEFINE A SIMPLE SOLUTION TO
A COMPLEX PROBLEM, THAT WOULD
BE LUCKY INDEED.
KIM BRUNHUBER, CBC NEWS TORONTO.
>> I WAS BORN IN GANDER AND CBC
WAS ALWAYS ON IN OUR HOUSE.
I NEVER DREAMED I WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FACES ON "HERE AND NOW".
A FILM SET IN RURAL
NEWFOUNDLAND COMES FULL CIRCLE
TONIGHT.
WHAT'S ON
>> Debbie: WELCOME BACK ONCE
AGAIN.
A WOMAN FROM THE PHILIPPINES
WHO HAS WAITED YEARS TO BECOME
A PERMANENT RESIDENT IS WORRIED
HER DREAM IS NOW IN JEOPARDY,
SHE HAS TRIED FOR FOUR YEARS TO
BRING HER YOUNG DAUGHTER TO
CANADA TO BE WITH HER.
WHAT'S TAKING SO LONG IS HER
DAUGHTER'S REVIEW BECAUSE SHE
IS DEAF.
>> GOOD MORNING.
HOW ARE YOU?
>> ACROSS THE DISTANCE AND TIME
ZONES THIS IS THE ONLY WAY
KAREN CAN SEE HER DAUGHTER IN
THE PHILIPPINES, BY SKYPE ONCE
A WEEK, SIGNING WITH
13-YEAR-OLD JASMINE, DEAF SINCE
BIRTH.
>> WOULD YOU LIKE TO COME HERE
TO CANADA?
>> HER MOTHER WATCHING AND
WORRYING FROM 11,000 KILOMETRES
AWAY.
>> IT'S SO FRUSTRATING THAT
I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR THIS LONG
ALREADY.
>> WIDOWED KAREN CAME TO CANADA
IN 2007 UNDER THE LIVE-IN CARE
GIVER PROGRAM TO SUPPORT
JASMINE JUST SIX MONTHS OLD.
SHE WORKED THREE NANNY JOBS TO
SEND HER DAUGHTER $1,000 A
MONTH.
SHE SAID JASMINE FACES A LIFE
OF DISCRIMINATION THERE, THAT'S
WHY SHE APPLIED FOR PERMANENT
RESIDENCY HERE IN 2010.
>> I HAVE TO DEAL WITH IT
BECAUSE IF I GO BACK HOME SHE
WON'T GET THE FUTURE.
>> THE PROBLEM, THE IMMIGRATION
ACT STATES THE FOREIGN NATIONAL
IS INADMISSIBLE IF THEIR HEALTH
CONDITION MAY PUT A DEMAND ON
HEALTH OR SOCIAL SERVICES.
BOTTOM LINE JASMINE WON'T BE
LET IN IF HER HEALTH CONDITION
COULD BE A BURDEN FOR CANADIAN
TAX PAYERS.
>> TO POSSIBLY REJECT A DEAF
GIRL IS WRONG.
>> I HATE TO THINK IF BEETHOVEN
CAME AND ASKED TO BE AN
IMMIGRANT WOULD WE DENY HIM
BECAUSE HE WOULD COST OUR
SYSTEM.
>> BUT THIS IMMIGRATION LAWYER
SAYS THE LAW IS THE LAW.
>> IF YOU SAY YES I WILL LET
THIS PERSON IN THEN YOU HAVE TO
BE PREPARED TO SAY YOU WILL LET
EVERYBODY IN AND THERE IS A
COST TO THAT.
>> ALWAYS BE A GOOD GIRL.
>> KAREN VOWS IF HER DAUGHTER
IS ALLOWED IN, SHE WILL SUPPORT
HER.
>> I LOVE YOU.
>> IF REJECTED KAREN
APPLICATION FOR PERMANENT
RESIDENCY WILL BE AUTOMATICALLY
REJECTED TOO.
ERIC RANKIN, CBC NEWS,
VANCOUVER.
>> Anthony: IF YOU THOUGHT
THERE WAS NOTHING NEW UNDER THE
SUN LOOK AT THIS.
THAT'S A TORNADO SEEN SPIRALING
OUT OF TOP OF A CLOUD.
EXPERTS HAVE HAD A COUPLE DAYS
TO EXAMINE IT AND NO ONE REALLY
KNOWS WHAT IT IS.
LIGHTNING HAS BEEN KNOWN TO
SHOOT-OUT OF THE TOP OF CLOUDS
BUT APPARENTLY IT'S OR SOLVE
THE CLOUD OF MYSTERY AROUND
THIS PHENOMENON.Fu#B
IF YOU HAVE EVER PLAYED DOMINOS
YOU WILL APPRECIATE OUR NEXT
STORY.
YOU ARE LOOKING AT AN EPIC SET
UP OF 22,000 DOMINOS.
IT TOOK FIVE DAYS TO SET UP AND
JUST TWO AND A HALF MINUTES TO
FALL DOWN.
WHO KNOWS HOW LONG IT WILL TAKE
TO CLEAN IT ALL UP.
>> THAT'S PRETTY AMAZING.
>> THAT IS A BIG CLEAN UP
THOUGH.
>> ESPECIALLY IF YOU WANT TO
KEEP THEM THE SAME COLOUR.
>> THE FUTURE IS NOW FOR
SPACEEX, THE PRIVATE SPACESHIP
BUILDER IN THE UNITED STATES.
THAT IS THE BIG REVEAL FOR THE
DRAGON V2 COOL NAME, ELON MUSK
SAYS THE SPACESHIP IS BUILT TO
CARRY SEVEN ASTRONAUTS TO THE
INTERNATIONAL SPACE STATION AND
BACK TO ERNL.
THE DRAGON IS ALSO ABLE TO
HOVER AND LAND IN A TAKE OFF
POSITION.rQUK
IT HAS A 1.6 BILLION CONTRACT
WITH N.A.S.A. TO SEND UNMANNED
SUPPLY SHIPS TO THE SPACE
STATION.
>> Debbie: WOW.
JUST AHEAD ZACH GOUDIE HAS THE
LATEST ON OUR INVESTIGATION
INTO A DOWNTOWN PROPERTY.
THE OWNER IS RAZING QUESTIONS.
>> POLICE IN GANDER ARE
INVESTIGATING A SEXUAL ASSAULT
OFF A 14-YEAR-OLD GIRL AND HOW
IT MAY HAVE STARTED AT LAST
WEEK AS SCI-FI CONVENTION.
>> WE ARE THE ONE WHO'S ARE
VICTIMS.

>> THIS IS ONE LUCKY DUCK.t
SEE HOW A NURSE GIVES CPR FIRST
AID TO A FINE FEATHERED FRIEND.
>> Anthony: POLICE ARE
INVESTIGATING A CASE OF SEXUAL
ASSAULT TO A 14 YIELD.
THAT'S WHERE "HERE AND NOW"'S
KRISSY HOLMES IS TONIGHT.
>> THIS TIME LAST WEEK THERE
WERE HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE HERE AT
NHOLIDAY INN FOR THE AN
-
SCI-FI AND ROCK CONVENTION.NUAL
LOOK AT THIS FOOTAGE.
THIS GIVES YOU AN IDEA THEY ARE
ALL AGES.CO
THE CONVENTION ITSELF IS
BASICALLY WALL-TO-WALL PEOPLE.
SATURDAY THE 14-YEAR-OLD GIRL
WAS AT THE CONVENTION AND AT
SOME POINT LATER THAT DAY SHE
ARRIVED IN GANDER WHERE THIS
SEXUAL ASSAULT IS SAID TO HAVE
TAKEN PL)&
÷
POLICE CONFIRMED IT TOOK PLACE
OVER THE SATURDAY-SUNDAY
PERIOD, SHE ARRIVED BACK IN
SAINT JOHN, THERE HAVE BEEN
REPORTS CALLING THIS AN
ABDUCTION BUT NEITHER ARE
WILLING TO LABEL IT THAT AT
THIS POINT.
THEY ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
HOW THIS GIRL GOT TO GANDER AND
SAY THEY ARE IT TAKES PLACE
OVER TWO THE R.N.C. ARE
ASSISTING WITH THERE'S ARE LOTS
OF RUMOURS FLYING AROUND ABOUT
WHO THE SUSPECTS ARE.
ONE OF THEM EVEN POSTED ON IF A
BOOK SAYING HE IS FEELING
TARGETED.
THEY ARE FOCUSING ON
INTERVIEWING WITNESSES WHO MAY
BE AUBL TO CONFIRM DETAILS OF
THE STORY.
WE REACHED OUT TO ORGANIZERS,
THEY DIDN'T GET BACK TO US, BUT
THE RCMP SAY THEY ARE HOPING TO
HAVE A STATEMENT FOR US READY
NEXT WEEK.
LIVE FOR "HERE AND NOW", I'M
KRISSY HOLMES IN St. JOHNS.
>> STUDENTS IN LABRADOR CITY
SAY THE TALK AT MINEHK HIGH
WERE SENT HOME TODAY.
THE SCHOOL
>> AN ENGINEER HIRED BY St.
JOHN'S LANDLORD MIKE O'DAY SAID
HE DOESN'T KNOW IF THE HOUSE AT
73 LONG'S HILL IS SAFE TO LIVE
IN.
O'DAY PROVIDED A LETTER FROM
PETER HUTTON CERTIFYING REPAIRS
TO PART OF THE HOUSE BUT HUTTON
SAID HE CAN'T CERTIFY THE HOW'S
IT SELF.
ZACH GOUDIE HAS BEEN FOLLOWING
THIS STORY AND JOINS US LIVE.
ZACH, WHAT IS IN THIS LETTER?
>> WELL IT WAS WRITTEN BY PETER
HUTTON AND ADDRESSED TO THE
CITY OF St. JOHNS.
AS WE REPORTED THIS WEEK, THE
CITY HAD IDENTIFIED MAJOR
STRUCTURAL PROBLEMS WITH THIS
HOUSE.
AFTER MIKE O'DAY BOUGHT HE WAS
TOLD IT WOULD HAVE TO BE
CERTIFIED BUT THAT DIDN'T
HAPPEN.
>> HE HAD BEEN WORKING ON THE
HOUSE AT 73 LONG'S HILL FOR
WEEKS.
ENGINEER PETER HUTTON SAID HE
INSPECTED THE RENOVATIONS ALONG
THE WAY.
IT WAS LIKELY BUILT IN THE LATE
80'S OR EARLY 90s, WE CAN'T SAY
FOR SURE BECAUSE THE WORK
APPEAR TO HAVE BEEN DONE UNDER
THE TABLE WITH NO CITY PERMITS
OR INSPECTIONS.
IT ALSO HAD NO FOUNDATION.
LAST FALL THE CITY CARRIED OUT
AN INSPECTION AND DEMANDED A
STRUCTURAL ASSESSMENT FROM AN
ENGINEER, PARSONS ENGINEERING
CONCLUDED THE ADDITION HAS
COMPROMISED THE STRUCTURAL
INTEGRITY OF THE ENTIRE
BUILDING.
FAST FORWARD HE CERTIFIES THAT
STRUCTURAL WORK MEETS OR
EXCEEDS THE REQUIREMENTS OF THE
NATIONAL BUILDING CODE OF
CANADA.
BUT WHEN WE SPOKE TO HUTTON HE
SAID HIS CERTIFICATION APPLIES
ONLY TO THE WORK ON THE
ADDITION, NOT TO THE STRUCTURAL
INTEGRITY OF THE ENTIRE
BUILDING.
HUTTON SAID HE WAS NEVER ASKED
TO ADDRESS THE BALANCE OF THE
STRUCTURE.
HE CAN'T SAY IF THE WORK THAT
WAS DONE IS ENOUGH TO MAKE THE
HOUSE SAFE.
>> LET'S SAY YOU HAD A HOUSE
LIKE THIS.
BASICALLY A BOX.
>> WE ASKED WILLIAM PARSONS,
THE ENGINEER WHO ASSESSED
>>
>> AND SAID JUST INVESTIGATING
WE HAVE TO GO IN, CALCULATE
WHAT SHOULD BE THERE PETER
HUTTON TOLD ME HE PENT,
MEANWHILE THE CITY STILL HASN'T
ACCEPTED HUTTON'S CERTIFICATION
AND PREPARING A REPORT ON
DEFICIENCIES AT THIS HOUSE FOR
MOIK
>> A REPORT DELIVERED TO HOY
DRO TODAY CONFIRMS FLEW KHANKS
CAUSED HUPDS OF PILLD MILLIONS.
TODAY'S REPORT COMES WITH SOME
RECOMMEND CAROLYN WHAT CAN YOU
TELL US IN
>> WELL, ANTHONY, HYDRO NEVER
DID DENY THE MILLIONS OF FUEL
WASN'T QUITE UP TO SNUFF.
IT MET THE INDUSTRY STANDARDS
AND THE SPECIFICATIONS IN THE
CONTRACT.
BUT IT HAD LEVELS OF ALUMINUM
AND SILICON HIGH ENOUGH TO
CAUSE CORROSION AT HOLY RUDD.
THIS EXPLAINS MORE ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED AND WHAT HYDRO PLANS
TO DO ABOUT IT.
HYDRO RECEIVED TWO SHIPMENTS OF
FUEL IN JANUARY AND FEBRUARY
LAST YEAR.
PURCHASED FROM A NEW OVERSEAS
SUPPLIER SOON AFTER THE MISH RY
STARTED EXPERIENCING PROBLEMS.
EIGHT DIFFERENT MECHANISMS FROM
INJECTION VALVES TO CLOGGED
FILTERS AND THEN TWO FUEL
SPILLS BECAUSE OF WEAR ON THE
TUBES.
THERE'S A VERBAL AGREEMENT TO
LOWER THE LEVEL OF ALUMINUM AND
SILICON.
THEY WILL HIRE A FUEL
CONSULTANT TO LOOK AT THE
SYSTEM AND EQUIPMENT DESIGNS.
THERE'S NO MENTION, BUT BACK IN
MARCH HYDRO WAS ADAMANT THE TWO
ISSUES WERE NOT CONNECTED.
REPORTING LIVE I'M CAROLYN
STOKES FOR "HERE AND NOW".
>> POLICE ARE INVESTIGATING A
CAR TORCHED AT TOP SAIL BEACH
BUT SAY THEY HAVE NO LEADS ON
WHO IS RESPONSIBLE.
THE BEACH IS A POPULAR SPOT BUT
ON SUNDAY NIGHT IT WAS ANYTHING
BUT PEACEFUL.
DONALD WAS THERE WITH HIS
GIRLFRIEND HAVING A BONFIRE.
TOO LATE TO SAVE HIS SUBURU.
>> CAME WALKING OUT OF THE
WOODS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN A BLAZE LIKE
THAT, I'VE SEEN BIG WOOD FIRES.
AND IT'S LIKE BURNING GASOLINE
BURNING CAR PARTS.
PIECES ARE POPPING.
THINGS ARE BURSTING.
IT WAS REALLY INCREDIBLE.
>> TWO OF THOSE FOXES FROM
SIGNAL HILL HAVE BEEN CAPTURED
AND NOW ON THEIR WAY TO A NEW
HOME.
FOXES WERE TRAPPED AND BEING
RELOCATED TO A REMOTE AREA.
FOR NOW THE TRAPS HAVE BEEN
TAKEN AWAY.
THE FOX'S NEW HOME IN A TOASTAL
AREA WHERE THEY CAN HUNT THEIR
OWN FOOD.
>> THIS IS A STORY YOU JUST
COULDN'T MAKE UP ABOUT A
DUCKLING AND NURSE WHO GAVE IT
MOUTH TO BEAK RESUSCITATION.
IT HAPPENED OUTSIDE THE CANCER
TREATMENT CENTRE OUTSIDE THE
HEALTH SCIENCES CENTRE WHEN
DUCK TRAINS MONDAY WAS NO
ORDINARY DAY FOR DOOF FEE KING.
NECESSITY SMTSED SOMETHING WAS
WRONG.
>> THERE WERE SEVEN DUCKLINGS,
THREE HAD FALLEN THROUGH THE
GREATS SO FOUR WERE WITH HER.
A COUPLE COLLEAGUES SCOOPED OUT
THE DUCKLINGS ONE BY ONE WHILE
MAMA AND THE OTHER DUCKLINGS
WAITED AND WATCHED THE RESCUE.
>> WHAT WE WORRY ABOUT THEM
GOING TO ANOTHER PLACE AND NOT
BEING ABLE TO REACH THEM.
>> SHE PUCKED UP NORTH DUCKLING
WHO DIDN'T THAT I SHE WAS GOING
TO MAKE IT.
I DID MASSAGE, TO GET
CIRCULATION AND I DID MOUTH TO
BAEK RESUS STATION I WAS QUITE
DELIGHTED SHE WAS ABLE TO BRING
THAT OTHER DUCKLING AROUND
BECAUSE IT DIDN'T LOOK LIKE IT
WAS DOING SO WELL.
CURIOUS IF THEY WOULD ALL MAKE
IT OR NOT.
>> BUT THEY ALL DONE.
SHE NAMED THE ONE SHE SAVED IF
I HAVE A CHOICE, WHETHER IT'S A
HUMAN OR ACREE TURE I WOULD
CHOOSE THAT ANY DAY.
>> THIS STORY HAS A VERY HAPPY
ENDING.
HUMANE SERVICES TELLS US MOM
AND DUCKLINGS HAVE BEEN DAFY
THE DUCKLING WAS RESCUE HERE ON
MONDAY.
>> FOR THE SECOND TIME THIS
MONTH, CREWS ARE CUTTING UP A
BLUE WHALE IN GROS MOURNE.
THIS TIME IT'S IN ROCKY HARBOUR.BñgY
I'LL HAVE THAT COMING UP ON
>> Debbie: WELCOME BACK TO
"HERE AND NOW".
IT'S NOT SOMETHING WE SEE OFTEN
BUT HERE IT HAS HAPPENED TWICE.
CREWS WERE CUTTING INTO A BLUE
WHALE AT ROCKY HARBOUR.
>> EVEN SPED UP CLEANING THE
BONES OF THE WORLD'S BIGGEST
CREATURE IS A HUGE PROCESS.
THIS TIME IT ATTRACTED THE
ATTENTION OF PAUL NADER, A
VETERINARIAN FROM NORTH
CAROLINA WITH A PASSION FOR
WHALES.
>> IN THAT PART OF THE
CONTINENT WE DON'T GET BLUE
WHALES.
WE GET FIN WHALES AND OTHER
>> FOR THE FIRST TIME IN HIS
LIFE HE DROPPED WHAT HE WAS
DOING AND FLEW TO NEWFOUNDLAND.
HE MADE A FEW DISCOVERIES.
IT'S CALLED A GROWTH PLATE.
HERS ARE ALL FUSED.
IT LOOKS TO ME SHE IS MORE THAN
MID 20'S.
HE CAN'T SAY FOR CERTAIN HOW
OLD BUT KNOWS SHE HAD A FEW
BACK PROBLEMS.
BETWEEN LUMBAR NUMBER THREE AND
NUMBER FOUR, THIS IS OSSIFIED
OR MINERALIZED, SHE DIDN'T HAVE
THE FLEXIBILITY SHE USED TO.
WHEN THEY WERE TAKING HER APART
IT BROKE RIGHT THERE.
BUT SHE HAD ARTHRITIS BETWEEN
L3 AND L4.
JACQUELYN MILLER OVERSEES THE
PROJECT.
NORMALLY SHE WORKS WITH SMALLER
ANIMALS.
>> IT'S BEEN REALLY INCREDIBLE.
QUITE INTERESTING TOO.
Xñ
I'VE NEVER WORKED ON ANYTHING
THIS BIG.
TODAY THE GOAL IS FINDING THE
HEART AND IT MAKES SENSE SINCE
THIS IS THE BIGGEST ANIMAL ON
THE EARTH IT WOULD HAVE A BIG
ONE.
PROBABLY CLOSE TO A TON AND
TALLER THAN A HUMAN.
>> THE BONES FROM THIS BLUE
WHALE WILL BE PUT IN A COOL
TRAILER AND SHIPPED TO ONTARIO
TO BE BURIED TO REMOVE THE
EXCESS OIL AND SKIN AND THEN
MAYBE SOME DAY THE je:
SIT ON DISPLAY AT MEMORIAL
UNIVERSITY.
JEREMY EATON, CBC NEWS, ROCKY
HARBOUR.
>> Debbie: UP ON THE NORTHEAST
COAST THERE IN THE THICK OF IT,
MORE THAN 100 ICEBERGS HUGGED
THE COAST YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
WOW.
>> I HAVEN'T SEEN THE LAST
NUMBER OF YEARS BUT THIS IS
UNBELIEVABLE.
WE HAVE NEVER SEEN THIS MANY,
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
WE CAN BLAME THE COOLER MAY
WITH THAT NORTHERLY PERSISTENT
WIND THAT HAS HELPED BRING THAT
DOWN THE COAST, KEPT THEM
NICELY TUCKED IN CLOSE TO THE
ISLAND AS WELL, NOW WE CAN
ENJOY THEM AS WE TURN THE
CORNER INTO JUNE.
THE GOOD NEWS AS I WILL EXPLAIN
WITH THE SEVEN DAY WINDS WILL
ROUND IN FROM THE SOUTH.
THAT WILL HAVE TEMPERATURES
WARMER TO ENJOY THE BERGS.
HAVE A LOOK.
LET'S START WITH YOUR DAYTIME
HIGHS.
21° IN BADGER, IF YOU WERE OFF
THE COASTENJOYING, 6° WITH AN
ON SHORE FLOW.
MUCH WARMER INLAND WHERE WE
WERE FLIRTING AGAIN.
3° TWILLINGATE.
HOTSPOT 23° IN CORNER BROOK.
LABRADOR CITY ACROSS TO HAPPY
VALLEY-GOOSE BAY.
AS WE TAKE A LOOK AT YOUR
CURRENT TEMPERATURES.
THE WINDS IN NOW FROM THE WEST.
STEPHENVILLE.
COOLED OFF TO 11° THIS
AFTERNOON ALL BECAUSE THE WIND
SHIFTED AND CAME IN OFF THE
WATER.
THE SEA BREEZE IS OBVIOUSLY A
HUGE STORY THIS TIME OF YEAR
AND THAT WILL BE THE STORY
AGAIN TOMORROW.
LOOK AT THE WINDS ALL FOR THE
MOST PART COMING IN FROM THE
WATER.
WE ARE LOOKING AT LIGHT WINDS
IN LABRADOR, THERE'S THE TROUGH
LINE, SINKING SOUTH.
THAT'S BEEN BUILDING THE CLOUDS
THROUGH THE WESTERN END AND
CENTRAL PARTS OF NEWFOUNDLAND.
A COUPLE SHOWERS FIRING UP
ALONG THAT AS WELL.
WE WILL ACTUALLY ZOOM IN AND
SHOW YOU A NICE BAND OF SHOWERS
WORKING IT'S WAY EASTWARD.
ACROSS LABRADOR.
THINGS CLEARING OUT NICELY.
ALL THE DISTURBANCE HERE IS TO
THE SOUTH.
COULD SEE FREEZING DRIZZLE.
AS WE WORK INTO THE AFTERNOON
TOMORROW, THAT TROUGH.
IT'S A SLIGHT RISK AT THAT.
ñ
BUT I DO EXPECT THE CLOUD >
TO KICK UP A LITTLE BIT IN THE
AFTERNOON, ESPECIALLY CENTRAL
AND EASTERN NEWFOUNDLAND.
THE SUN WILL STILL BE BREAKING
THROUGH.
SUNDAY MORE IN THE WAY OF
SUNSHINE ACROSS THE ISLAND, MIX
OF SUN AND CLOUD, SOME SHOWERS
RIDING INTO LABRADOR BUT
EVERYBODY STAYS WARM.
YOUR 7-DAY AND SUNDAY DETAILS
ARE COMING UP.
THERE'S THAT CHANCE OF SHOWER
OVER CENTRAL NEWFOUNDLAND
TONIGHT.
THE RISK THROUGH St. ANTHONY OF
A PERIOD OF FREEZING DRIZZLE
EVEN A WET FLURRY MIXING IN AND
CLEARING OUT QUITE NICELY IN
LABRADOR.
YOUR 7-TO-7.
WE WILL LOOK AT INLAND
TEMPERATURES IN THE 13-15 RANGE
ACROSS THE AVALON.
WITH THE SOUTH, SOUTHEASTERLY
WIND IN THE AFTERNOON KICKING
IN.
INLAND WE ARE IN THE DOUBLE
DIGITS.
17-18 HERE.
16° CORNER BROOK.
SHOULD SEE MORE SUN THAN CLOUD
INTO THE AFTERNOON.
7-9.
18 TO 16 ACROSS THE INTERIOR, A
CHANCE OF he$$A MORNING FLURRY,
YOUR SEVEN DAY IS STILL AHEAD.
>> WE ARE THE ONES WHO ARE
VICTIMS.
>> A YOUTH CARE COMPANY WANTS
TO LOCATE A FOSTER HOME ON THIS
QUIET CUL-DE-SAC BUT SOME
RESIDENTS ARE SAYING NO WAY.
COADE
>> Anthony: WELCOME BACK TO
"HERE AND NOW".
WE TOLD YOU ABOUT SENIORS WHO
DON'T WANT GROUP HOME IN THEIR
NEIGHBOURHOOD.
THE YOUNG PEOPLE WHO LIVE IN
THOSE NEIGHBOURHOODS ARE
>> ALEX STAPLETON HAD NO IDEA
THE PLACE NEXT DOOR WAS SOLD TO
BLUE SKY, A GROUP HOME.
>> WE LIVED HERE Baáñ49 YEARS AND
WE DESERVE TO BE LEFT ALONE AND
LIVE THE REST OF OUR LIFES IN
COMFORT.
>> THE YOUNG GIRLS AREN'T HAPPY
EITHER, THEY DON'T WANT TO
RELOCATE FROM THEIR PLACE IN
BURIN.
THEY WERE TOLD THEY WILL HAVE
TO GO SOMEWHERE ELSE UNTIL THE
ISSUE WITH THE NEW HOME'S
NEIGHBOURS IS CLEARED UP.
>> OUR LIFES ARE IN TURMOIL.
IT'S HARD.
>> THEY ARE ALSO UPSET AND
FRUSTRATED BY THE REACTION OF
THE RESIDENTS.
>> IT'S BEEN SAID THAT THE
GROUP HOME SHOULDN'T BE THERE
BECAUSE WE ARE TROUBLED
TEENAGER AND JUST HAVE A LOT OF
ISSUES.
THAT'S NOT TRUE, I'M NOT A
TROUBLED TEENAGER.
>> IT'S WHO COULD BE PLACED IN
THE HOME NEXT THEY ARE
CONCERNED WITH.
BLUE SKY IS A YOUTH CARE
COMPANY THAT TAKES CARE OF
VARIOUS FOSTER KIDS FROM THOSE
NEEDING TEMPORARY ACCOMMODATION
TO THOSE DEALING WITH SERIOUS
TROUBLES.
>> RIGHT NOW THEY ARE GOING SAY
WE ARE PUTTING FOUR GIRLS DOWN
HERE.
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN SIX
MONTH'S OR YEAR'S TIME?
SIX YEAR'S TIME?
WE HAVE HARDENED CRIMINALS WE
COULD HAVE SIX OFFENDERS WE
COULD HAVE ANYONE LIVING NEXT
YOOR.
--  DOOR.
>> THEY SAY CALLING IT A FOSTER
HOME INSTEAD OF A GROUP HOME AS
A BUSINESS THEY SEEM TO BE ABLE
TO MOVE IN WITHOUT PERMITS,
ZONING PERMITS.
>> THIS IS RESIDENTIAL AREA
ZONED.
>> THE MARYSTOWN COUNCIL HELD
TWO MEETINGS FOR CONCERNED
RESIDENTS.
A VOTE WILL HAPPEN THIS TUESDAY.
>> THE OWNER OF BLUE SKY IS
RESPONDING WITH A STATEMENT.
ANNE WHALEN SAID GROUP AND
FAMILY CARE HOMES ARE ALLOWED
IN RESIDENTIAL PROPERTIES AND
COMMUNITIES AND SAYS NO PERMIT
IS REQUIRED TO PROVIDE FOSTER
CARE IN A RESIDENTIAL
NEIGHBOURHOOD.
SHE SAID THEY TRY TO BALANCE
WITH THE RIGHTS OF THE CHILDREN
IN COMPANY'S CARE.
>> COOKING CURRY TO SEND KIDS
TO SCHOOL.
THAT'S WHAT A GROUP DID TODAY.
THEY CATERED A LUNCH AND MADE A
BIG DIFFERENCE FOR STUDENTS IN
INDIA.
"HERE AND NOW"'S AMY STOODLEY
REPORTS.
>> THEY ARE COOKING INDIAN FOOD
AND PACKING LUNCHES TODAY.
>> HERE IN St. JOHN IT'S JUST
ANOTHER MEAL BUT HUNDREDS OF
THOUSANDS OF MILES AWAY THESE
LUNCHES WILL CHANGE LIVES.
>> WE HAVE SOLD ABOUT 165 LUNCH
BOXES WHICH IS REALLY GREAT.
BECAUSE THROUGH THESE FUNDS WE
CAN SPONSOR FIVE THROUGH THE
SCHOOL YEAR.
>> HIS FAMILY IMMIGRATED TO
CANADA ABOUT TEN YEARS AGO.
NOW HE WANTS TO GIVE BACK.
>> I WENT BACK TO INDIA FOR THE
FIRST TIME AND I WAS SEVEN.
I SAW TWO KIDS ABOUT MY AGE
BEGGING FOR FOOD.
THE FIRST THING I THOUGHT WHEN
I SAW THIS WAS THESE KIDS
SHOULD BE IN SCHOOL.
I GO TO SCHOOL, MY FRIENDS GO
TO SCHOOL.
AND THESE KIDS INSTEAD OF
BEGGING THEY SHOULD MAYBE GO TO
SCHOOL AND IMPROVE THEIR LIVES.
BUT FOR KIDS IN THE SOUTHERN
INDIAN VILLAGE IT'S NOT THAT
EASY.
>> THEY NEED ENOUGH TO FEED
THEMSELVES AND PUT ENOUGH ON
THE TABLE.
THIS IS WHAT PREVENTS MOST
CHILDREN FROM GOING TO SCHOOL.
>> BUT THERE IS A WAY.
THANKS TO A GRADUATE OF
MEMORIAL UNIVERSITY.
AFTER DR. CHANDRA LOST HIS
FAMILY IN THE AIR INDIA BOMBING
IN 1985 HE WEPT BACK TO HIS
WIFE'S VILLAGE IN SOUTHERN
INDIA AND BUILT A SCHOOL.aa÷÷t
WITHOUT THEM REALLY, THIS
FUNDRAISING WOULDN'T HAVE GOT
TO WHERE IT IS.
>> IT'S NOT AS HARD AS YOU
THINK.
MAYBE CHANGE ONE LIFE IN INDIA,
MAYBE THAT'S WHERE IT WILL
START.
YOU LOOK AT THESE HUGE PROBLEMS
AND SAY WHERE CAN I START, WHAT
CAN I DO.
A STUDENT IN St. JOHN.
BUT IF YOU ARE CHANGING ONE OR
TWO KIDS LIVES THAT'S CHANGING
SOMETHING AND STARTING TO BREAK
THAT CYCLE OF POVERTY.
>> JUST ANOTHER MEAL HERE BUT
EDUCATION FOR YOUNG PEOPLE IN
INDIA.
AMY STOODLEY, CBC NEWS, St.
JOHNS.
>> THE RESPONSE HAS BEEN
OVERWHELMING.
>> A FILM SET IN RURAL
NEWFOUNDLAND COMES FULL CIRCLE
TONIGHT.
>> IT'S REALLY LIKE A
CELEBRATION, WE ARE PROUD TO BE
PART OF THAT.
>> WHAT'S ON
>> Anthony: WELCOME BACK.
STILL AHEAD THIS HALF HOUR,
ALAN HAWCO WITH "REPUBLIC OF
DOYLE" SITS DOWN WITH  --
>> Debbie: ONE DRIVER HAS DIED
WHILE CUTTING A SEARCH ACCESS
HOLE.
SEARCH AND RESCUE TEAMS HAVE
BEEN WORKING AT THE SITE SINCE
APRIL 16th.
MORE THAN 300 PEOPLE ARE DEAD
OR ARE STILL MISSING.
THE DIVER WAS PULLED TO THE
SURFACE AFTER THEY HEARD A
MYSTERIOUS BOOM COME FROM HIS
RADIO DEVICE.
>> RENOWNED HUMAN RIGHTS
ACTIVIST JORDIN TOOTOO IS IN
ALBERTA TO ATTEND A CONFERENCE,
AFTER HIS TOUR OF THE OILPATCH
HE SHARED HIS THOUGHTS ON
RELATIONS BETWEEN THE TWO
GROUPS.
>> HOPE VERY MUCH THAT HOPE
WILL SPREAD FROM THIS
CONFERENCE.
THAT PEOPLE WILL SEE IT'S
BETTER, WORKING TOGETHER.
THE SOUTH AFRICAN NOBEL PRIZE
LAUREATE WILL GIVE A SPEECH,
TOOTOO HAS TAKEN A STRONG STAND
ON CLIMATE CHANGE AND SPOKEN
OUT AGAINST PROJECTS LIKE THE
KEYSTONE XL PROJECT IN THE PAST.
>> A TWIST ENDING LAST NIGHT AT
THE U.S. NATIONAL SPELLING BEE.
>> E-U-I-L-L-E-T-O-N.
>> CORRECT.
>> THAT SURE LOOKS LIKE A
VICTORY.2A;
NOT SO FAST, THE 7th GRADER AND
HIS RIVAL WERE PERFECT THROUGH
ALL THE DESIGNATED CHAMPIONSHIP
WORDS SO THE JUDGE HAD TO
DECLARE IT A DRAW, SOMETHING
THAT HASN'T HAPPENED IN OVER 50
YEARS.
THEY BOTH WON $30,000 PLUS THE
SHOUT OUT ON TWITTER FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
>> Anthony: LONG TIME FRONT MAN
IS GIVING UP HIS DAY JOB TO
SPEND MORE TIME ON STAGE.
DENNIS PARKER IS GIVING UP HIS
GIG AT THE END OF JUNE.
HE SAYS IT'S TIME TO RESURRECT
HIS MUSIC CAREER.
>> Anthony: TODAY IN St. JOHN
THE VOLUNTEER KNOWN AS THE
DRIVING FORCE BEHIND AUTISM
SOCIETY RECEIVED AN HONORARY
DEGREE FROM THE UNIVERSITY.
CHURCHILL RECEIVED HER
DOCTORATE OF LAW DEGREES THIS
MORNING.
TODAY IS A DAY FRANCOPHONES IN
NEWFOUNDLAND AND LABRADOR
CELEBRATE THEIR FRENCH AND
ABORIGINAL LANGUAGE AND CULTURE.
IT DATES BACK MORE THAN 500
YEARS.
THOUGH FRANCOPHONES REPRESENT
JUST 0.5% OF THE POPULATION.
>> Debbie: A MOVIE SHOT IN
RURAL NEWFOUNDLAND COMES FULL
CIRCLE TONIGHT.
THE GRAND SEDUCTION IS OPENING
IN THEATRES ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
INCLUDING IN A THEATRE NOT FAR
FROM WHERE THE FILM WAS MADE.
>> WE HAVE NO IDEA HOW TO PLAY
CRICKET.
>> THE MOVIE PAIRS LOCAL ACTORS
WITH SOME INTERNATIONAL STARS.
IT'S A STORY ABOUT A SMALL TOWN
GOING TO GREAT LENGTHS TO KEEP
A VISITING DOCTOR.
THE GRAND SEDUCTION WAS FILMED
NEAR BONAVISTA AND PEOPLE THERE
WILL GET TO SEE THEIR HOME AND
SOME NEIGHBOURS ON THE BIG
SCREEN TONIGHT.
"HERE AND NOW"'S LINDSEY BIRD
REPORTS.
>> SINCE IT'S RESTORATION, A
FEW YEARS AGO, THE HISTORIC
THEATRE HAS BECOME THE "IT
SPOT" ON THE PENINSULA THEATRE
BUT THIS MIGHT TOP EVERYTHING.
BUT THESE SEATS ALMOST DIDN'T
GO ON SALE AT ALL.
THE GARRICK WAS LEFT OFF THE
ORIGINAL DISTRIBUTION LIST FOR
"THE GRAND SEDUCTION" FIRST RUN.
A SOCIAL MEDIA CAMPAIGN TURNED
THAT AROUND AND NOW A MOVIE
SHOT NEARBY IS COMING TO FULL
CIRCLE.
>> TO BRING "THE GRAND
SEDUCTION" TO THE GARRICK
BRINGS A SENSE OF PRIDE.
>> THE MAIN ACTORS MAY BE
ABSENT BUT SOME OF THE MOVIE
EXTRAS WILL BE IN THE AUDIENCE.
STILL SAVORING THAT EXPERIENCE.
>> YOU DON'T REALIZE HOW MUCH
WORK GOES INTO MAKING A MOVIE,
WHEN YOU WATCH THE MOVIE FROM
THE THEATRE YOU JUST SEE
CERTAIN THINGS BUT WHEN YOU ARE
ACTUALLY INVOLVED YOU SEE
DIFFERENT THINGS.
>> WE HAVE NO IDEA HOW TO PLAY
CRICKET.
>> HE SAYS THE CRICKET SCENE
WAS PARTICULARLY FUN TO FILM
BUT NOW HE HAS A FEW
PRE-PREMIER JITTERS ABOUT BEING
SEEN BY FRIENDS AND FAMILY ON
THE BIG SCREEN.=
JUST ANOTHER THING ON THE
BUCKET LIST.
>> THE MOVIE ALSO STARTS
SCREENINGS IN St. JOHNS TONIGHT
BUT IF YOU WANT THE FULL GRAND
SEDUCTION EXPERIENCE IT'S
PLAYING HERE AT THE GARRICK FOR
THE NEXT WEEK.
LINDSEY BIRD, CBC NEWS,
BONAVISTA.
>> Debbie: I CAN'T WAIT TO SEE
IT.
YOU HAVE SEEN IT.
>> Anthony: IT'S A FEEL-GOOD
MOVIE AND THE SCENES OF
NEWFOUNDLAND ABSOLUTELY
BREATHTAKING.
>> Debbie: THAT'S FANTASTIC.
WELL GOOD LUCK WITH THAT.
>> Anthony: CASE CLOSED.
WE WILL SET UP THE FINAL
>> Anthony: WELCOME BACK.
LAST NIGHT WE TOLD YOU "THE
REPUBLIC OF DOYLE" WILL BE
WRAPPING UP.
ALLAN HAWCO SAYS IT'S THE RIGHT
TIME.
FOR FIVE YEARS DOYLE FANS HAVE
TUNED IN TO WATCH THEIR
FAVOURITE PRIVATE EYE GET IN
ALL KINDS OF TROUBLE, SOMETIMES
WITHOUT A SHIRT.
IT'S HELPED GROW A LOCAL
PRODUCTION INDUSTRY BUT FOR NOW
ALAN HAWCO AND THE CAST WILL
BEGIN SHOOTING THEIR FINAL
SEASON.
ALLAN HAWCO IS JUST BACK FROM
TORONTO AND HE IS WITH DEBBIE.
>> Debbie: THANK YOU.
YOU ARE STRAIGHT FROM THE
AIRPORT.
YOU JUST GOT BACK FROM TORONTO.
>> YES I WOULDN'T MISS IT.
THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> Debbie: YOU SAID THE TIME
WAS RIGHT TO CALL IT QUITS
AFTER THE SEASON.
WHY?
>> WE HAVE BEEN WORKING ON THE
SHOW FOR FIVE YEARS, GOING INTO
SIX.
PERRY CHAFE AND I AND ROB WE
ALL DECIDED WE WANTED TO GO OUT
ON OUR TERMS THAT CREATIVELY WE
DIDN'T OVER EXTEND THEMSELVES
AND GAVE OUR AUDIENCE THE
BIGGEST BANG FOR THEIR BUCK, WE
WORRY IF WE TRIED TO KEEP IT
ALIVE TOO LONG WE MIGHT BE
DOING A DISSERVICE TO THESE
CHARACTERS AND THEIR STORY.
I NEVER WANT TO BE THAT PERSON
WHO, PEOPLE HAVE GROWN FATIGUED
WITH WHAT WE ARE DOING OR GET
ANNOYED WITH WHAT WE ARE DOING.
STILL FEEL WE HAVE A REALLY
STRONG BASE.
WE HAVE TEN EPISODES FOR OUR
LAST SEASON STARTING IN OCTOBER.
EVEN PEOPLE WHO HAVE LEFT THE
SHOW FOR A LITTLE WHILE THIS IS
AN OPPORTUNITY TO COME BACK AND
TAKE US BACK WITH A BANG.
>> YOU HAVE A BIG CREW THAT
WORKS ON DOYLE.
HOW ARE THEY TAKING IT?
AT LEAST WE ARE ABOUT TO WRITE
OUR OWN ENDING.
>> Debbie: I KNOW YOU AREN'T
GOING TO TALK ABOUT THE STORY
LINES, I JUST KNOW THAT.
BUT YOU HAVE HAD BIG STARS THAT
HAVE DROPPED IN AS GUESTS.
ANYTHING LIKE RUSSELL CROWE OR
ANYBODY YOU CAN NAME AS COMING
BACK?
>> IT'S ALWAYS SO FUNNY BECAUSE
I ALWAYS WANT TO TELL YOU
EVERYTHING BUT I NEVER CAN.
I WILL TELL YOU JASON OWE MARE'
MARRA A GREAT IRISH ACTOR IN
THE FIRST EPISODE.
ALAN DOYLE, SEAN DOYLE WILL BE
BACK, A LOT OF DOYLES.
OLD FAVOURITES.
JAKE IS IN TROUBLE AT THE END
OF THE SEASON.
WE HAVE TEN EPISODES TO JAM
EVERYTHING WE WANTED TO DO TO
END THE SERIES SO WE ARE HAVING
FUN.
>> Debbie: WE ARE LOOKING
FORWARD TO THE LAST SEASON
COMING UP BUT I QUICKLY WANT TO
GET TO THE FACT YOU jwH?ñARE DOING A
LOT OF THINGS, SHOT PART OF A
MOVIE SHOT IN SOUTH AFRICA.
THE BOOK OF NEGROES.
BY LAWRENCE HILL.
HERE IS A QUICK CLIP OF THE
MOVIE.
>> COOL.
>> IT WAS FUN TO BE ON SOMEONE
ELSE'S SET WHERE I COULD PLAY
AN EXTREMELY DIFFERENT
CHARACTER.
HE IS BRITISH, JEWISH SLAVE
TRADER VERY DIFFERENT FROM JAKE
DOYLE, A LOT OF FUN AND EX
SIDING BUT IT DID REMIND ME I
LIKE WORKING HERE WITH OUR CREW
AT HOME ON OUR PROJECTS MORE
THAN ANYTHING.
FINGERS CROSSED SEASON SIX AND
WE ARE DEVELOPING A LOT OF
OTHER THINGS AS WELL.
HOPEFULLY I WILL HAVE OTHER
THINGS TO TELL YOU SOON.
>> Debbie: AND "THE BOOK OF
NEGROES" WHEN WILL WE SEE THAT?
>> I THINK JANUARY.
I HAVEN'T SEEN ANYTHING.
I HOPE IT'S GOOD.
HOPE I'M NOT TERRIBLE.
>> Debbie: I'M SURE YOU'RE NOT
AND WE LOOK FORWARD TO THAT AND
ALL THE OTHER THINGS THAT ARE
PERCOLATING WITH ALAN HAWCO.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
AND THANK YOU FOR OUR AUDIENCE
FOLLOWING US FOR ALL THESE
YEARS.
THANKS FOR ALL OF THE SUPPORT.
>> Ryan: ONE THING YOU KNOW
WHEN YOU ARE WATCHING "REPUBLIC
OF DOYLE" IT'S ALWAYS BEAUTIFUL
IN NEWFOUNDLAND AND St. JOHNS.i%xJt
YOU KNOW, THIS WEEKEND WILL BE
A GREAT SHOOTING FOR ANY OF US
WHO WANT TO TAKE PICTURES OF
ICEBERG.=R[Qñ
JET STREAM DIPPING TO THE NORTH.
THE HEAT IS ON IN THE PRAIRIES,
STILL COOL WITH THE JET STREAM
TO THE SOUTH.
BUT THE DAYTIME HEATING HELPING
WARM US UP THIS TIME OF HERE.
WE ARE INTO CLOUD COVER.
CLOUDY WITH SUNNY PERIODS TYPE
OF A DAY.
THE EXCEPTION IN THE EAST, COOL
WITH A SEA BREEZE.
INLAND WELL INTO THE DOUBLE
DIGITS.h
>> Anthony: WELCOME BACK TO
"HERE AND NOW", 100 YEARS AGO
HE WAS DRIVEN OUT OF
NEWFOUNDLAND AS A SUSPECTED
GERMAN SPY.
THE ARTIST ROCKWELL KENT MAY
NOT HAVE FOUND HIS PLACE HERE
BUT HIS LEGACY HAS FOUND IT FOR
HIM.
>> THE OPENING EVENT WAS THE
SCREENING OF THE ROOMS OF A
DOCUMENTARY ON ROCKWELL KENT.
NOT AN EASY TASK BECAUSE KENT
WAS NOT AN EASY MAN.
>> I THINK HE WAS PROBABLY SIX
OR SEVEN DIFFERENT PEEM.
>> HE WAS A CEASELESS WONDER
WHO SOUGHT OUT SOME OF THE
WORLD'S CRUELEST CLIMATE AND
CAPTURED THEM ON CANVAS.
>> HE CAME FOR THE SOLITUDE OF
THE WILD BOTH IN NATURE AND
HUMANS.
HE THOUGHT HE FOUND IT IN ÔÑ
BRIGUS WHERE HE LIVED AND
WORKED FOR ONE YEAR.
SOME ARE MORE FAN TAFT CAL AND
AL GORE CAL.
TO MY KNOWLEDGE HE DIDN'T
REALLY DO THAT EXPERIMENTATION
AFTER HE LEFT NEWFOUNDLAND.
>> Azzo: A COLLECTION OF HIS
WORK OPENS AT THE ROOMS THIS
EVENING.
CURATOR CAROLYN STONES BELIEVES
THE HARSH REALITY AND BEING
WITNESS TO THE GREAT CEILING
DISASTER HAD A HUGE INFLUENCE
ON HIM.
>> I THINK BEING AWAY FROM NEW
YORK AND IN A PLACE WHERE HE
COULD DO WHAT HE WANTED WHEN HE
WANTED, HOW HE WANTED WITHOUT
AN AUDIENCE REALLY MADE HIM
ABLE TO EXPERIMENT.
>> HE COULD BE AFFABLE, HE
COULD ALSO BE SO FULL OF
HIMSELF AND HEARTY PRACTICAL
JOKES HE HAD EVERYONE IN BRIGUS
CONVINCED HE WAS A GERMAN SPY.
HE WAS ADVISED TO LEAVE FOR HIS
OWN GOOD.
AND SO HE TOOK OFF AGAIN LIKE A
FLIGHT AFTER AN EMERGENCY
LANDING BUT LEING BEHIND A
STORY INTRIGUING ENOUGH TO BE
RETOLD 100 YEARS LATER.
>> Debbie: CAROLYN STOKES JOINS
US NOW WITH A LOOK AT "HERE AND
NOW" LATE NIGHT.
>> Carolyn: AFTER YEARS OF
WAITING AND SEEING OTHER TOWNS
BUILD HOCKEY ARENAS, GOVERNMENT
HAS GIVEN THE GO AHEAD FOR IT
TO START CONSTRUCTION ON A NEW
ARENA, SO WE WILL GET REACTION
AND FIND OUT WHAT TOOK SO LONG.
"HERE AND NOW" LATE NIGHT IS
ONLINE ONLY BECAUSE OF HOCKEY.
SO YOU CAN SEE IT AT cbc.ca/nl.
SO RYAN, ANY GOOD NEWS FOR THE
WEEKEND?
>> Ryan: DEFINITELY.
BRIGHT AND SUNNY.
TEMPERATURES A LITTLE ON THE
COOL SIDE HERE IN THE EAST.
CENTRAL YOU HAVE A GREAT
WEEKEND SHAPING UP.
WARMER FOR THE CENTRAL PARTS OF
THE ISLAND AND WEST COAST.
THINGS CLEAR UP BUT COULD GET
TO 20° IN HAPPY VALLEY-GOOSE
BAY SUNDAY AFTERNOON AS THAT
WARM FRONT AND SOUTHERLY FLOW
COME IN.
LOOKS LIKE HILLS WITH PERHAPS
SNOW CAPPED ON THE MOUNTAINS
THERE, A GREAT RAINBOW AND I
LOVE THAT MR. SUNSHINE THERE IS
WINKING AT US.
STICKING HIS TONGUE OUT.
>> Debbie: AND NOW IT'S TIME TO
FIND OUT WHO IS CELEBRATING
THIS WEEK.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO SAMMY PENNEY
OF CARBONEAR.
>> LOTS OF BIRTHDAYS.
LOVELY LOOKING CROWD, AS ALWAYS.
>> Debbie: CAROLINE SAID HER
PROGRAM IS ONLINE BECAUSE OF
HOCKEY.
ARE YOU CRYING BECAUSE OF THE
HABS.
>> Ryan: GREAT SEASON, YOU HAVE
TO GIVE PROPS TO TOKARSKI.
>> Anthony: THERE'S ALWAYS NEXT
YEAR.
>> Ryan: THAT'S WHAT I'VE BEEN
SAYING ABOUT LEAFS FANS FOR
YEARS.
>> Debbie: ONE MORE WEEK FOR
JONATHON, HAVE A GREAT WEEK.
GOOD NIGHT.