>> TONIGHT THE CITY OF ST.
JOHN'S BUYS BACK LAND IT GAVE
TO THE BOY SCOUTS.
WHAT DOES COUNCIL PLAN TO DO
WITH IT?
>>> HE'S BEEN DRIVING CANCER
PATIENTS TO DOCTORS
APPOINTMENTS FOR 30 YEARS AND
TONIGHT HIS VOLUNTEER WORK WAS
RECOGNIZED.
>>> GOOD EVENING AND WELCOME TO
"HERE AND NOW LATE NIGHT."
I'M CAROLYN STOKES.
>>> ST. JOHN'S CITY COUNCIL
WILL SPEND 770,000 TO GET BACK
A PIECE OF LAND IT GAVE TO THE
BOY SCOUTS OF CANADA FOR $1 30
YEARS AGO.
THE PURCHASE INCLUDES THIS
BUILDING AND SOME LAND NEAR THE
OLD METRO BUS DEPOT.
THE CITY HASN'T DECIDED WHAT TO
DO WITH IT YET.
THE DECISION TO REAPPROPRIATE
AFTER FINDING OUT THE CANADIAN
MENTAL HEALTH ASSOCIATION
WANTED TO BUY THE LAND FOR ITS
NEW HEADQUARTERS.
CITY COUNCILLORS SAY THEY'RE
AWARE OF THE GOOD WORK THE
ASSOCIATION DOES AND WANT TO
HELP FIND A SOLUTION.
>> WE ARE IN A DIALOGUE WITH
THE ASSOCIATION TO FIND AN
APPROPRIATE SPACE FOR THEM AND
TO THAT POINT THERE'S LOTS OF
OPTIONS AND I'LL JUST LEAVE IT
AT THAT FOR NOW.
WE'RE CERTAINLY IN DISCUSSIONS
AND I LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING
WITH THEM BECAUSE AS A CITY AND
AS A COUNCIL WE'RE COMMITTED TO
MENTAL HEALTH AND I THINK WE
DON'T WANT TO SEND THE WRONG
MESSAGE HERE.
WE'RE CERTAINLY WILLING TO WORK
WITH THEM AND HELP THEM FIND
SOMETHING VERY APPROPRIATE.
>> POLICE WILL BE KEEPING WATCH
OVER THE SCENE OF THE SUDDEN
DEATH EARLIER TONIGHT.
IT HAPPENED IN THE HOME ON
CASEY STREET.
THE R.C.M.P. SAY THERE IS
NOTHING TO INDICATE THE DEATH
IS SUSPICIOUS BUT OFFICERS WILL
STAY THERE OVERNIGHT UNTIL THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER CAN GET A
FIRSTHAND LOOK TOMORROW.
>>> MHA KIRBY WON THE
NOMINATION IN ST. JOHN'S NORTH.
HE BEAT CHALLENGER SHAWN LANE.
KIRBY WAS ELECTED AS A MEMBER
OF THE NDP BUT CROSSED OVER TO
THE LIBERALS AFTER THE DISPUTE
OVER PARTY LEADERSHIP.
>>> AND THE CITY OF ST. JOHN'S
ANNOUNCED THE WINNER OF THE 4TH
ANNUAL SENIOR OF THE YEAR AWARD
AT COUNCIL TONIGHT.
THIS YEAR'S WINNER IS FRASER
ELLIS.
FOR 30 YEARS HE'S VOLUNTEERED
TO DRIVE CANCER PATIENTS TO AND
FROM APPOINTMENTS.
HE'S ALSO WORKED WITH BRIDGES
TO HOPE, THE JANEWAY HOSPITAL
AND TURNINGS.
ELLIS USED HIS MOMENT IN THE
SPOTLIGHT TO ACKNOWLEDGE OTHER
HARD-WORKING VOLUNTEERS HE SAYS
ARE JUST AS DESERVING OF THE
AWARD.
>> HUNDREDS OF OTHER PEOPLE
INCLUDING HARRY UP THERE AND
MARY WHO SPENDS HOURS IN ST.
CLAIRE LOOKING OVER SENIOR
PEOPLE.
MY WIFE HERE WHO IS MY GUIDING
LIGHT AND HELP HER TO HELP OUT
WHENEVER POSSIBLE AND THE
HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY.
THEY'RE ALL OVER THE PLACE NOW.
ALL WE NEED IS MORE OF THEM!
AND THAT'S WHAT I OFTEN SAY.
WE NEED MORE PEOPLE TO DO
VOLUNTARY WORK IN EVERYTHING.
AND FOR ALL THOSE, I ACCEPT
THIS TRUTHFULLY.
ON BEHALF OF ALL THOSE THAT DO
AS MUCH OR MORE THAN I'VE EVER
DONE, THANK YOU ALL VERY MUCH
FOR THIS.
>> Carolyn: THE FEDERATION OF
LABOUR SAYS IT WAS DOUBLE
CROSSED BY GOVERNMENT TODAY.
IT HAS TO DO WITH THE PROPOSED
AMENDMENT TO THE LABOUR
RELATIONS ACT.
THAT AMENDMENT WOULD ELIMINATE
UNION CARD BASED CERTIFICATION
THAT ALLOWS TO FORM IN THE WORK
PLACE WHEN ENOUGH EMPLOYEES
SIGN CARDS OF SUPPORT.
FEDERATION OF LABOUR IS
ACCUSING THE GOVERNMENT OF FLIP
FLOPPING AND SAYS SHE WILL
DEMAND A MEETING WITH THE
PREMIER TO DISCUSS IT.
>>> WELL, GOVERNMENT HAS LOST A
KEY CABINET MINISTER.
JOAN SHAY ANNOUNCED HER
RESIGNATION FROM POLITICS TODAY
AND THE PREMIER IS WARNING SHE
WON'T BE THE LAST.
THE CBC'S PETER COWAN HAS THAT
STORY.
>> THE COLLEAGUES IN THE TORY
CAUCUS GATHERED TO HEAR HER
GOODBYES.
A NEW LEADER IS COMING IN FOR
THE TORY PARTY AND THE LEAD UP
TO THE NEXT ELECTION WILL BE A
TIME OF CHANGE.
AS OF NOW I'M ANNOUNCING I'M
LEAVING AND I EXPECT NEW PEOPLE
TO COME IN AND LEAD AS WELL.
>> OTHERS HAVE WANT TOD GO BUT
SAY THEY'RE PRESSURED TO STAY.
IT MEANS MORE SUCCESS FOR THE
PICKING UP THE SEATS FROM THE
PCs.
THE PARTY DOESN'T WANT TO BE
SEEN AS WEAK LEADING INTO THE
NEXT GENERAL ELECTION.
BURKE SAID HER DECISION TO
LEAVE JUST CAME IN THE LAST FEW
DAYS.
>> YOU NEED ENERGY AND
ENTHUSIASM TO DO THIS JOB AND
WHEN YOU BEGIN TO FEEL TIRED
IT'S TIME TO STEP ASIDE AND LET
OTHERS STEP UP.
>> FIRST ELECTED MORE THAN A
DECADE AGO WITH JOAN BURKE AND
BEEN IN CABINET EVER SINCE AND
SERVE AS THE MINISTER FER
EDUCATION AND THE FIRST WOMAN
EVER TO BE NAMED GOVERNMENT
HOUSE LEADER.
THE PREMIER TODAY SAID HE'S
PROUD OF ONE PARTICULAR
ACCOMPLISHMENT.
>> THE POVERTY REDUCTION
STRATEGY IS PROBABLY THE ONE
I'M PLEASED ABOUT THE MOST.
IT WAS INITIATIVE THAT'S HELD
UP ACROSS THE COUNTRY AS A
MODEL FOR ALLEVIATING,
PREVENTING, REDUCING POVERTY
AND MINISTER BURKE WAS THE
MINISTER THAT LED THAT.
>> Carolyn: AND THAT REPORT WAS
FROM THE CBC'S PETER COWAN.
>>> WELL, 5 FISHERMEN ARE SAFE
WITH THEIR FAMILIES AFTER
RUNNING INTO TROUBLE OFF THE
NORTHEAST COAST YESTERDAY.
THE CBC'S LINDSEY BYRD MET WITH
ONE OF THE PILOTS THAT RESCUED
THEM.
>> THE ICE OFF THE NORTHEAST
COAST IS THICK AND DANGEROUS.
THAT TINY BLACK DOT IN THE
MIDDLE THE SINKING DLL FEATURE.
THEY MADE THE DISTRESSING CALL
AT 5:30 AND ABANDONED IN THE
LIFE RAFT.
>> WE HAD A LOT OF PRESSURE ON
US TO GET OUT THERE QUICKLY
BECAUSE THE INFORMATION THAT WE
HAD SAID THAT NOT EVERYONE HAD
SUITS ON THE CREW AND THE WATER
OUT IN NEWFOUNDLAND RIGHT NOW
IS STILL REALLY COLD AND IT
REALLY DOES MAKE A DIFFERENCE
IN CASES LIKE THESE.
>> Reporter: ONE HOUR LATER THE
SEARCH AND RESCUE CREW FOUND
THE MEN SAFE ON THE ICE FLOW.
BUT THE RESCUERS HAD A PROBLEM.
THEIR POWERFUL HELICOPTER.
>> Interview: OUR CONCERN WAS
HOVERING OVER THEM IN THE
MACHINE THAT CREATES SO MUCH
ROTOR WASH WE MIGHT FLIP OVER
THE ICE AND WE HAD TO STAY 100
METRES BACK MAKING SURE WE
WON'T BLOW THE ICE OVER WHICH
AT THAT POINT WE WOULD MAKE THE
SITUATION WORSE.
>> FLYING EXTRA HIGH MADE THE
RESCUE MORE CHALLENGING.
TO ACCURATELY DROP THE BASKET
DOWN TO THE FLOW.
BUT WITH GOOD WEATHER ON THEIR
SIDE, THEY HOISTED UP EACH MAN
ONE BY ONE.
>> THEY HAD A HARD TIME.
THEY'RE BOTH JUST IN THE WATER
AND THEY DIDN'T KNOW THEY WOULD
BE RESCUED NECESSARILY.
>> THE MEN MAY HAVE BEEN SHAKEN
FROM THEIR ORDEAL BUT THEY WERE
UNHURT.
THE CHOPPER DETOURED TO THE SEA
TO DROP THEM OFF TO THE WAITING
AND ANXIOUS LOVED ONES.
WHILE THE 5 FISHERMEN ARE NOW
SAFE, THEY'RE STILL UP IN THE
AIR.
WHEN THE HELICOPTER LEFT THE
SCENE OF THE RESCUE, IT WAS
PARTIALLY SUBMERGED.
NO WORD YET ON WHETHER THAT'S
BEEN ABLE TO BE SALVAGED.
LINDSEY BYRD, CBC NEWS, GANDER.
>> ALL THAT ICE OFF SHORE IS A
PROBLEM FOR FISH HARVESTERS AND
THEIR UNION HELD FROM OTTAWA.
THE ICE CONDITIONS HAVE KEPT
MANY BOATS DOCKED SINCE APRIL
AND THAT MEANS NO INCOME.
THE FISHERIES UNION SAYS THE
SITUATION IS GETTING DESPERATE
AND THEY'RE CALLING FOR
EMERGENCY AID THROUGH THE
EMPLOYMENT INSURANCE PROGRAMME.
>> THE PRACTICAL PURPOSES TO
THE INDIVIDUALS GETTING
EXTENDED AND THAT'S THE
SIMPLEST AND MOST EFFICIENT WAY
OF DOING IT AND I REALLY DON'T
KNOW WHAT THE DELAY IS AND IT'S
VERY OBVIOUS.
ALL SOMEONE HAS TO DO IS GO OUT
AND LOOK OFF THE END OF THE
WARF ON SOME OF THESE NORTHERN
COMMUNITIS AND THEY'RE JAMMED
IN BY ICE.
GO TO THE FLY AROUND.
OBVIOUSLY THERE'S NO RELIEF IN
SIGHT.
>> WELL, ICEBERGS ARE ALSO A
BIG ATTRACTION AND THE
BONAVISTA IS A PRIME PLACE TO
GO.
THE CBC'S LEE PITTS TAKES US
THERE.
>> Reporter: THE FIRST OF THE
ICEBERGS COMES INTO FOCUS AS
YOU DRIVE DOWN THE BONAVISTA
PENINSULA.
NEARBY IN KINGS COVE MORE OF
THEM.
JUST AT THE MOUTH OF THE
HARBOUR OVERSHADOWING THE
FISHERMEN.
>> I'VE BEEN SEEING THE
ICEBERGS AROUND THE PROVINCE
AND I DIDN'T BELIEVE IT.
I BELIEVE IT NOW.
>> DRIVE ALONG THE PENINSULA
TOWARDS BONAVISTA AND THEY
BECOME MORE PLENTIFUL AND MUCH
LARGER.
TALL, MAJESTIC.
TOWERING HIGH BELOW THE WAVES
BELOW.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING FOR QUANTITY
CAPE BONAVISTA IS THE PLACE TO
BE.
FROM HERE YOU CAN COUNT MORE
THAN 70 ICEBERGS DOTTING THE
HORIZON.
>> IT'S CERTAINLY A GIFT FROM
CREATION.
>> FROM CAPE BONAVISTA, THERE
ARE ICEBERGS IN EVERY DIRECTION.
>> UNTIL WE COME OUT HERE AND
SEE 20 ICEBERGS, THEY HAD TO GO
IN.
IT'S AN AMAZING THING.
>> IT'S NOT JUST A SIGHT FOR
VISITORS.
THOSE FROM HERE ARE IN AWE.
>> Reporter: WE LOOK OUT THE
KITCHEN WINDOW AND SEE FROM 18
TO 20 WHERE WE'RE AT.
>> Interview: HE'S 74 AND SAID
HE'S NEVER SEEN ANYTHING LIKE
IT IN HIS LIFETIME.
>> Reporter: ALL SHAPES AND
SIZES.
NO TWO ALIKE.
AND EACH PERSON SEES SOMETHING
DIFFERENT.
>> IT'S LIKE A CHURCH AND
ANOTHER ONE I TOOK WAS LIKE IN
A FOREST.
JUST BEAUTIFUL.
>> Reporter: BUT THERE MAY BE
ONE MAJOR DRAWBACK TO THESE
ICEBERGS.
THEY'RE CALLED NATURE'S AIR
CONDITIONING SO IT'S QUITE
CHILLY.
LEE PITTS, CBC NEWS, THE
BONAVISTA PENINSULA.
>> Ryan: I'M HERE AND NOW
METEOROLOGIST RYAN SNODDEN IN
THE WEATHER TRACKING CENTRE
TRACKING A PRETTY GOOD LOOKING
TUESDAY ESPECIALLY ACROSS THE
ISLAND WITH WARM TEMPS AND THE
SUN IN THE MIX.
THE FULL DETAILS AFTER THE
BREAK.
FIRST A LOOK AT YOUR CURRENT
TEMPERATURES.
>> Carolyn: NOW RYAN SNODDEN
WITH THE WEATHER FORECAST AND
SOUNDS LIKE CLOUDS TOMORROW.
>> Ryan: WE'RE REALLY CLEARING
QUITE NICELY INTO TOMORROW
AFTERNOON AND TEMPERATURES BACK
ON THE RISE AGAIN AND THE FACT
THAT EVEN THROUGH THE WEEK WE
ARE GOING TO CLOUD UP A LITTLE
LATE IN THE WEEK BUT THE
TEMPERATURES STAY WARM ALL WEEK
LONG.
MORE SUN IN THE MIX FOR TUESDAY
AND THEN WE DO TURN UNSETTLED
AS WE WORK INTO THE
WEDNESDAY-THURSDAY-FRIDAY TIME
PERIOD BUT LOOKING PRETTY GOOD
INDEED IN TERMS OF THOSE
TEMPERATURES SO THE COLD FRONT
SLICES THROUGH AND BRINGING A
COUPLE OF SHOWERS IN THE
SOUTHEAST LABRADOR TONIGHT.
MAINLY WITH THE CLOUD COVER
ACROSS THE ISLAND AND THE
CLOUDS BREAKING UP INTO THE
AFTERNOON AND LOOKING AT A
REALLY NICE ONE WITH THE SEA
BREEZE A BIT OF A FACTOR AGAIN
AND THE TEMPERATURES ARE NICE
WITH THE FORECAST IN JUST A
SECOND.
BUILDING CLOUDS AND SHOWERS
ROLLING INTO LABRADOR'S WORK
THROUGH TUESDAY NIGHT INTO
WEDNESDAY AND EVEN THE ISLAND
WILL BE SEEING GOLDEN CLOUDS
WITH SHOWERS AND DRIZZLE
CREEPING IN ON TUESDAY NIGHT
INTO WEDNESDAY WHICH WILL BE
MORE UNSETTLED.
AND WEDNESDAY INTO THURSDAY
WE'RE LOOKING AT THE SAME KIND
OF A SOUTHERLY FLOW SINCE
PATCHY DRIZZLE AND SHOWER
ACTIVITY BUT THE SHOWERS REMAIN
WARM FOR ALL OF THE ISLAND AND
EVEN INTO PARTS OF LABRADOR.
HERE'S HOW THE 7 TO 7 PLAYS OUT
FOR TOMORROW AND STARTING OUT
AT 4 AND SHOULD BE 17 TO 20
WITH THE TEMPERATURES IN THE
METRO REGION TOMORROW.
SO THE SEA BREEZE SHOULD BE
LESS OF A FACTOR.
TODAY THE WINDS FROM THE
SOUTH/SOUTHEAST SO HUGE
TEMPERATURE DIFFERENCES AND GO
OUT TO 19 IN PARADISE BUT ONLY
GOT TO 8 IN THE BAY.
TOMORROW THE WIND IN FROM THE
SOUTH/SOUTHWEST AND THERE
SHOULD BE LESS OF THAT SEA
BREEZE AND MORE OF AN ON SHORE
FLOW FOR THE ST. JOHN'S METRO
REGION SO WE SHOULD SEE
TEMPERATURES CLIMB A LITTLE BIT
WARMER FOR TOMORROW AND THAT'S
THE GOOD NEWS.
THE BEST CHANCE OF 20 DOWN TO
CBS IN WHITBURN AND THAT'S
WHERE TEMPS WILL LIKELY PEAK.
WE'LL SEE TEMPERATURES IN THE
DOUBLE DIGIT MARKET AND DOWN
THROUGH PLACENTIA.
18 THROUGH THE BURIN AND
THROUGH THE CLARENVILLE REGION
INTO GANDER AND CENTRAL WITH
THE HIGH TEENS AND LOW 20s AND
THE CLOUD COVER CLEARING IN THE
AFTERNOON.
SUN AND CLOUDY MUCH THROUGH TO
THE END OF THE DAY WITH THE
WEST COAST AND THE TEMPERATURES
COOLER ON THE SOUTH COAST AND
PRETTY NICE UP INTO THE
NORTHERN PENINSULA AND HAPPY
VALLEY-GOOSE BAY CLEARING AND
IN TERMS OF HOW THINGS PLAY
OUT, AS I MENTIONED, STAYING
WARM AND IN FACT THURSDAY AND
FRIDAY FACTORING IN A LITTLE
BIT OF HUMIDITY AND FEELING
SUMMER LIKE FOR THURSDAY AND
FRIDAY.
IT WILL FEEL INTO THE LOW 20s.
CENTRAL AND WESTERN
NEWFOUNDLAND AGAIN CLOUDING UP
ON WEDNESDAY AND THIS IS FAR
FROM THE WASH OUT WITH THIS
SYSTEM BUT CERTAINLY THE CLOUD
COVER WILL BE DOMINATING AS WE
WORK OUR WAY TOWARDS THE
WEEKEND WHERE WE'LL SEE THINGS
CLEAR OUT AND COOL DOWN ON THE
OTHER SIDE OF THE SYSTEM.
EASTERN AND WESTERN LABRADOR
GETTING CLOUDY WITH SHOWERS IN
THE MIX AND CLEARING OUT AS WE
WORK OUR WAY TOWARDS THE
WEEKEND.
THAT IS THE FORECAST FOR NOW.
CAROLYN, BACK TO YOU.
>> THANKS, RYAN.
>>> GOOD NEWS IF YOU'RE ABOUT
TO BOOK A PLANE TICKET TO
LONDON.
AIR CANADA IS BRINGING BACK
DIRECT FLIGHTS TO HEATHROW AND
NOT JUST FOR THE SUMMER.
CHRIS O'NEILL-YATES REPORTSES.
>> Chris: STARTING IN LATE
OCTOBER THEY'LL BE FLYING
STRAIGHT TO LONDON HEATHROW.
THEY TRIED BEFORE AND IT DIDN'T
FLY SO WELL BUT ONE OF THE
MAJOR DIFFERENCES IS THEY SAY
THEY'LL HAVE A SMALLER AIRCRAFT.
THEY'LL USE AN AIR BUS WHICH
CARRIES 120 PASSENGERS.
IF THESE CUPCAKES STAMPED WITH
THE UNION JACK WEREN'T THE
SPOILER, THIS AIR CANADA
EXECUTIVE GAVE AWAY THE PLOT.
TO AN AUDIENCE THAT'S BEEN
LOBBYING FOR A CONNECTION FROM
ST. JOHN'S TO LONDON.
>> Interview: IT'S ALWAYS AIR
CANADA'S INTENTION TO EXTEND IT
TO A YEAR-ROUND OPERATION AND
WE FEEL NOW IS THE TIME TO DO
THAT.
>> Reporter: THE ST. JOHN'S
AREA HAS ONE OF THE STRONGEST
ECONOMIES IN THE COUNTRY.
IT'S REFLECTED AT THIS AIRPORT
WHERE GROWTH IS THE THIRD
HIGHEST IN THE COUNTRY.
A MILLION AND A HALF PASSENGERS
CAME THROUGH HERE LAST YEAR.
UP 23% IN THE PAST 5 YEARS.
>> Interview: WE HAVE SEEN A
STRONG INCREASE IN CONSUMER
DEMAND.
>> Reporter: AND SIMPLY PUT AIR
CANADA THINKS IT CAN MAKE MONEY
THIS TIME.
>> Interview: THIS IS THE
COMMERCIAL DECISION ON THE PART
OF AIR CANADA AND VERY
CONFIDENT AND THE MARKET WILL
SUPPORT THE YEAR ROUND SERVICE.
>> IT'S A REALLY NICE WAY TO
START.
THAT GIVES US THIS OPPORTUNITY
TO PROVE TO AIR CANADA THAT
THIS IS A VIABLE ROUTE
LONG-TERM.
>> Reporter: THEY SAY THE
TIMING COULDN'T BE BETTER FOR
THE OIL SECTOR.
>> IT IS THE BASIN AND
CERTAINLY THE CONNECTIONS ARE
GOING TO BE EACH MORE IMPORTANT
AND IT'S REALLY, REALLY GREAT
TO SEE THIS CHANGE.
>> Reporter: UNLIKE THE
PREVIOUS FLIGHT, THIS ONE ISN'T
OUT OF HALIFAX.
IT STARTS OCTOBER 26TH AND WILL
OPERATE ON MONDAY, THURSDAY AND
SATURDAYS.
>> ONE THING MANY PEOPLE WANT
TO KNOW, ARE THERE ANY HOT
DEALS BETWEEN ST. JOHN'S AND
LONDON?
I ASK THE REGIONAL VP TODAY AND
THEY DIDN'T HAVE ANYTHING TO
ANNOUNCE ON THAT IN PARTICULAR
BUT HE'S SURE THAT THE
MARKETING TEAM WITH AIR CANADA
IS WORKING ON
>> HE'S REALLY PASSIONATE ABOUT
IT AND MAKING A DIFFERENCE.
>> INSPIRING A NEW GENERATION
FOR RECYCLERS.
THE MAN BEHIND CANS FOR KIDS
GETS A SURPRISE TOMORROW ON
HERE AND NOW.
>> Carolyn: A BODY CHECK TODAY
TO THE PROGRESSIVE
CONSERVATIVES FROM LONG-TIME
TORY JOHN CROSBY.
HE SAYS THE CONSERVATIVES ARE
IN DEEP TROUBLE HEADING INTO
THE NEXT ELECTION.
CROSBY SAYS THE PARTY'S
REPUTATION HAS BEEN DAMAGED
BECAUSE NO ONE IS OPPOSING
INCOMING PREMIER FRANK COLEMAN.
HERE'S WHAT HE HAD TO SAY.
>> AND THE MEMBER OF THAT PARTY
WITH THE EVENTS FOR THE LAST 3
OR 4 MONTHS.
IF THE PARTY CANNOT PUT
TOGETHER AN INTERESTING
LEADERSHIP CONVENTION, THERE'S
SOMETHING FUNDAMENTALLY WRONG.
THIS IS WHAT HAPPENED.
WE ENDED UP WITH TWO WITH NO
PHYSICAL EXPERIENCE WHATSOEVER,
NEVER BEEN BLOCK CAPTAINS OR
INSPIRED THEM AND IT'S THE
INTEREST FOR THE PEOPLE IN THE
CONTEST AND WE KNOW THAT THE
PREMIER, THE FORMER PREMIER,
AND FORMER PREMIER DANNY WHO 7
YEARS AGO ANNOUNCED THAT HE WAS
RETIRING AS PREMIER.
NO ONE FORCED HIM OUT.
HE MADE THE DECISION AND IT'S A
SURPRISE TO EVERYONE AND AFTER
7 YEARS HE HAD DECIDED 7 YEARS
IS ENOUGH AND HE WAS LEAVING
POLITICS AND HE WAS GOING ON IN
THE PRIVATE LIFE, ET CETERA.
AND GETTING OUT OF THE BUSY
SCENE AND THEN FOR SOME REASON
OR OTHER HE STILL WANTS TO HAVE
INFLUENCE.
>> YOU FEEL LIKE HE HASN'T
ACTUALLY LEFT POLITICS.
>> HE HASN'T LEFT POLITICS.
HE'S STILL UP TO HIS NECK AND I
KNOW HE HAS PERSUADED, WHEN HE
CAME OUT PUBLICLY AGAINST MR.
BARRY, WHICH HE SHOULD NEVER
HAVE DONE, HE'S A FORMER
PREMIER AND SHOULD NEVER HAVE
INTERVENED AGAINST OR FOR ANY
CANDIDATE.
HE SHOULD HAVE BEEN NEUTRAL.
THAT'S THE USUAL PROCEDURE.
HE CAME OUT AGAINST ONE OF THE
CANDIDATES AND HE'S BEEN VERY
ACTIVE EVER SINCE IN WHAT'S
HAPPENING SO THE REASON THE PC
PARTY IS IN NOW IS BECAUSE OF
HIS INFLUENCE.
>> AND DANNY WILLIAMS RESPONDED
IN AN E-MAIL TO CBC.
HE SAYS HE'S AT A LOSS TO
UNDERSTAND WHERE CROSBY IS
COMING FROM.
WILLIAMS SAYS A NUMBER OF
PEOPLE FROM THE PC CAUCUS AND
CABINET INITIALLY CALLED HIM TO
EXPRESS INTEREST IN THE
LEADERSHIP AND HE ENCOURAGED
ALL OF THEM TO GET INVOLVED.
WILLIAMS SAYS HE EVEN AGREED TO
MEET WITH CROSBY'S SON WHO HAD
ALSO CONSIDERED RUNNING FOR THE
LEADERSHIP.
>>> WELL, THE HEBRON PROJECT
REACHESES AN IMPORTANT PHASE
TOMORROW.
THE HUGE GRAVITY-BASED
STRUCTURE IS BEING BUILT AT THE
DRY DOCK.
STARTING TOMORROW THE DRY DOCK
WILL BE FLOODED IN PREPARATION
TO MOVE THE STRUCTURE INTO DEEP
WATER.
THE CBC'S ZACH GOUDIE TAKES US
THERE.
>> Reporter: THE HEBRON PROJECT
HAS ALREADY COME A LONG WAY.
FROM THE DRAWING BOARD TO THE
DRY DOCK.
FOR OVER A YEAR NOW 5 ENORMOUS
POWERED CRANES AND OVER 2,000
CONSTRUCTION WORKERS HAVE BEEN
MOVING PIECES OF THE
GRAVITY-BASED STRUCTURE INTO
PLACE.
CONCRETE IT POURED ONE RING AT
A TIME RAISING THE STRUCTURE
TOWARDS ITS FINAL HEIGHT OF 160
METRES.
>> SO THIS IS A VERY EXCITING
TIME FOR THE HEBRON PROJECT.
WE'VE COMPLETED THE FIRST STAGE
OF CONSTRUCTION IN THE DRY DOCK.
>> Reporter: BUT STAGE 2 OF
CONSTRUCTION IS GOING TO LOOK 0
DIFFERENT.
FROM DUSTY AND DIRTY TO WET AND
WILD.>> Interview: WHAT'S GOING
TO HAPPEN IS WE'LL PUT WATER IN
THE DRY DOCKS AND NEXT MONTH
THIS PART OF THE GRAVITY-BASED
STRUCTURE WILL MOVE TO WHERE
THE CONSTRUCTION WILL CONTINUE.
>> Reporter: THE RETAINING WALL
WILL BE SCOOPED UP LETTING THE
WATER RUSH IN.
THE STRUCTURE WILL FLOAT SO
WHEN THE WATER LEVEL IS RIGHT,
IT WILL BE TOWED INTO THE
NEARBY HARBOUR.
>> Interview: YOU KNOW, WE SET
THE TARGET FOR FLOATING OUT OF
THE DRY DOCK TO BE THIS SUMMER.
WE SET THE TARGET 3 YEARS AGO
AND WE'RE MEETING THAT TARGET.
>> PARKER SAYS THE BRUTAL
WINTER PUT THAT TIME LINE IN
JEOPARDY.
HE CREDITS THE WORKERS WHO
BRAVED THE COLD AND THE SNOW
FOR KEEPING THINGS ON SCHEDULE.
THIS TIME LAST YEAR THE
GRAVITY-BASED STRUCTURE WAS
JUST GETTING OFF THE GROUND.
NOW HALF THE STRUCTURE IS
COMPLETE.
BUT IT WON'T BE FITTING ON THE
GROUND MUCH LONGER.
>> I THINK EVERYONE SHOULD BE
>> Carolyn: THOUSANDS OF
ANGLERS ARE GEARING UP TO FISH
IN THE PROVINCE'S 183 SALMON
RIVERS.
THE SEASON OPENED THIS WEEK AND
DFO HAS CHANGED THE WAY IT
CLASSIFIES WHERE ANGLERS CAN
KEEP SALMON AND WHERE IT MUST
BE RELEASED.
SOME SALMON-FISHING VETERANS
SAY THE SECRET TO LANDING THE
BIG ONE IS CHOOSING THE RIGHT
FLY.
>> THIS IS NONE OF YOUR
BUSINESS.
ONE OF THE BEST FLIES THE PAST
COUPLE OF YEARS FOR WEST COAST
NEWFOUNDLAND.
>> NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS?
>> NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS.
>> AND OTHERS?
>> NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS AND
MIND YOUR BUSINESS.
>> WELL, POLICE ARE WARNING
PEOPLE ABOUT A POLAR BEAR THAT
HAS COME ASHORE NEAR ST.
ANTHONY.
ACMP HAVE RECEIVED A CALL ABOUT
A SIGHTING 8 KM  FROM THE TOWN.
THIS PICTURE TAKEN BY STEVE
CASEY NEAR TRIPLE FALLS.
THEY WARN ANYONE IN THE PARK TO
BE EXTRA CAUTIOUS WITH CHILDREN
AND PETS AND BE ON THEIR GUARD.
>>> AND A MARATHON OF A TRIAL
HAS BEEN SET FOR SUPREME COURT
IN ST. JOHN'S NEXT JANUARY.
IT'S THE HICKMAN EQUIPMENT
FRAUD CASE.
IT'S SLATED FOR ABOUT 6 MONTHS.
4 FORMER SENIOR MANAGERS ARE
FACING 16 CHARGES.
EACH OF WHICH A FRAUD OVER
$5,000 AND FALSIFYING DOCUMENTS.
IN THE EARLY TWO THOUSANDS
HICKMAN BUT THE SHORT-LIVED
COMPANY WENT BANKRUPT IN 2002.
CREDITORS ARE STILL OWED MORE
THAN 90 MILLION DOLLARS.
CHARGES WEREN'T LAID UNTIL 2012.
>>> AND OF COURSE YOU CAN CHECK
OUT ALL THE LATEST NEWS AND
WEATHER ANY TIME YOU LIKE
ONLINE AT CBC.CA/NL
THAT'S OUR SHOW FOR TONIGHT.
I'M CAROLYN STOKES.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR WATCHING.